<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</origin>
        <pubdate>200501</pubdate>
        <title>AMS China Lan-Ts'ang Region</title>
        <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-ams7810-s250-u54-nf47-7</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This layer is a geo-referenced raster image of the Army Map Service 1:250,000 scale China series topographic map of the Lan-Ts'ang region. This map (NF47-7) was compiled in 1956 from: USAF Approach Chart Base Compilation 1:250,000, ACIC, Charts 556 B II and 616 A I, compiled 1954 and was first printed in this series in August 1957.

Please note that this map title is an outdated (Wade-Giles romanization) spelling of the Chinese place or feature name for which the map is named.  Both this outdated version and the current Pinyin romanization version appear as Place Keywords in this metadata record.

A digital raster graphic (DRG) is a scanned image of a standard series topographic map, including all map collar information. The image inside the map neatline is geo-referenced to the surface of the earth and fit to the Universal Transverse Mercator projection. The horizontal positional accuracy and datum of the DRG matches closely with the accuracy and datum of the source map.

This map series of China (Series L500) was created and printed by the US Army Corps of Engineers Army Map Service (AMS) during the 1950s. The AMS was later known as the Defense Mapping Agency, which is now subsumed under NIMA. 
These maps are a contoured topographic map series based largely on the Survey of India. These color maps have contour intervals of 100 meters. Map sources used to create these maps include British Survey of India maps, Japanese civil survey and military maps; United States Air Force (USAF) and United States Hydrographic Office (USHO) charts and a variety of other source maps simply described as the "... best available large scale and medium scale maps of China."
These maps are in English, with modified Wade-Giles romanized Chinese place and feature names, many names also appear as Chinese ideographs.  These are typical topographic maps with all of the normal topographic information: contours, transportation, culture, etc. Please pay close attention to map collar information on projections, spheroid and keys to grid numbering and other numbers which appear inside the neatline.</abstract>
      <purpose>One of the most widely used of all maps is the topographic map. The feature that most distinguishes topographic maps from maps of other types is the use of contour lines to portray the shape and elevation of the land. Topographic maps render the three-dimensional ups and downs of the terrain on a two-dimensional surface.
Topographic maps usually portray both natural and manmade features. They show and name works of nature including mountains, valleys, plains, lakes, rivers, and vegetation. They also identify the principal works of humans, such as roads, boundaries, transmission lines, and major buildings.
The wide range of information provided by topographic maps make them extremely useful to professional and recreational map users alike. Topographic maps are used for engineering, energy exploration, natural resource conservation, environmental management, public works design, commercial and residential planning, urban planning and design, and outdoor activities like hiking, camping, and fishing. These maps can provide an excellent view of the changes that have occurred in the cultural and physical landscape.  As this map has been geo-referenced, it may serve as a useful basemap in conjunction with other GIS data.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>200502</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>98.830274</westbc>
        <eastbc>100.682306</eastbc>
        <northbc>23.097159</northbc>
        <southbc>21.780094</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Maps, Topographic</themekey>
        <themekey>Land Use</themekey>
        <themekey>Infrastructure</themekey>
        <themekey>Human settlements</themekey>
        <themekey>Bodies of water</themekey>
        <themekey>Landforms</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>GNS (NIMA)</placekt>
        <placekey>China</placekey>
        <placekey>Lan-Ts'ang</placekey>
        <placekey>Yuan-Chiang</placekey>
        <placekey>Yunnan Province</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.  Although this data set has been developed  by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</cntorg>
          <cntper>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard Map Collection</address>
          <address>Pusey Library</address>
          <address>Harvard University</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 9:00 A.M. to 4:00 P.M. EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 4; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.0.0.535</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>In regards to the original paper maps: Road classification should be referred to with caution.  Vegetation information is generally unreliable on many of these maps and the delineation of international boundaries is not considered authoritative.

The DRG is a 24-bit per pixel color image that employs a color palette to ensure uniform colors throughout a particular DRG series. All DRGs within a series must have the same RGB value.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <complete>The DRG is a faithfully reproduced digital image of the original source map. Some differences may be detected between the source graphic used and the DRG due to the RGB values assigned that particular color.  The intent is to recreate those colors as near as possible. Data completeness for DRG files reflect content of the source graphic.

All of the AMS Series L500 maps have edition dates and one or more printing dates. Each map also cites its source material which may or may not be dated on the piece. Use these dates to determine the vintage of the cartography.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The positional accuracy of the orginal map was largely preserved during the digitizing and geo-referencing  processes. Accuracy may be generally characterized as possessing the highest standards of accuracy given the general survey, instrumentation, design and printing technologies and cartographic techniques available during the time the original map was produced.  The original map was scanned and geo-referenced (SEE: Process Steps) to produce this digital version.

While the data of the published map is retained in the georeferenced image, the image is referenced to the Universal Transverse Mercator coordinate system, which is inconsistent with the original projection of the paper map, and may lead to discrepancies in the horizontal accuracy of the DRG.  The standard used for georeferencing the image to the UTM coordinates was an RMS error below 50 meters.  See the process steps for the actual RMS error achieved.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Refer to the DRG collar for information about vertical positional accuracy.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Army Map Service</origin>
            <pubdate>1950s</pubdate>
            <title>AMS Topographic Map</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>250,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>195708</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>AMS Topo Map of China</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Original Map was scanned and digitized in preparation for geo-referencing.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Harvard Map Collection</origin>
            <pubdate>200412</pubdate>
            <title>AMS Topographic Map (Digitized Version)</title>
            <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>250,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>computer program</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>200502</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>AMS Topo Map (Digitized Version)</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The digitized version of the AMS Topo Map was georeferenced and a world file (.tfw) was created.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Production of this Digital Raster Graphic (DRG) began with the scanning of the paper topographic map on a high-resolution scanner (Betterlight, Super8K2 scanning back camera and ViewFinder 5.x capture software).

Maps were photographed at a copy stand. A vacuum easel was used to keep the maps flat during photography. The imaging specification was designed to produce detailed "Archival Master" images that, to the extent possible, are faithful reproductions of the originals, and that allow for highly detailed screen reproduction and print reproduction at up to 1:1.

Files were edited in and saved from Adobe Photoshop CS. When possible files were batch processed using an "action" script derived from edits applied to match a representative sample.  Color and tonal corrections were made using Curves, Levels, and Hue/Saturation filters in Adobe Photoshop. 

Image files were viewed on a calibrated monitor. Editing was performed in an ISO 3664 compliant proofing environment. Master Image files were corrected and archived as TIFF files (compliant with the TIFF 6 Specification) in the sRGB IEC611966-2.1 color-space.  Files were saved with an embedded profile. The colorspace tag is used to assure that color and tonal information is properly displayed across multiple systems and media.

Image resolution is of sufficient quality to render all meaningful map details on screen and in print; Format is 24 bit Tiff, uncompressed; Tone/color reproduction: embedded ICC (International Color Consortium) profile with associated size and tone reference. Quality control: visual inspection, MD5 checksum for 100% of images.</procdesc>
        <srcused>AMS Topo Map (Paper)</srcused>
        <procdate>200412</procdate>
        <srcprod>AMS Topo Map (Digitized Version)</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard College Library</cntorg>
              <cntper>Digital Imaging and Photography Group</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>D-Level, Room D-30</address>
              <address>Widener Library</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2030</cntvoice>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>This digital image was geo-referenced to a shapefile containing the four sets of UTM grid coordinates nearest to the corner tics of each map image.  The coordinates were projected in UTM_WGS_1984 with the appropriate UTM Zone (44_N through 51_N).  Because the AMS did not publish this map series with an associated horizontal datum, the widely used WGS_1984 datum was applied to each image in order to provide a consistent, standardized coordinate system to use across the entire collection of AMS L500 Series China maps.  Horizontal accuracy is therefore not as good as it would be if the datum(s) were known.  ArcMap 9.0 was utilized to georeference the image to the four projected control points, and a .tfw (world file) was generated.  The RMS error was recorded and a world file (automatically generated by ArcMap) was saved in association with the scanned image.  The horizontal positional accuracy of a DRG is approximately the same as the accuracy of the published source map. However, there may be errors introduced during the digitizing and geo-referencing process. In most cases, errors in the DRG are small compared with sources of error in the original map graphic.

The RMS error for this map is: 25.77504 meters.

RMS: The degree to which the transformation can accurately map all control points can be measured mathematically by comparing the actual location of the map coordinate to the transformed position in the raster. The distance between these two points is known as the residual error. The total error is computed by taking the root mean square (RMS) sum of all the residuals to compute the RMS error. This value describes how consistent the transformation is between the different control points (links). The RMS error is only an assessment of the accuracy of the transformation.</procdesc>
        <srcused>AMS Topo Map (Digitized Version)</srcused>
        <procdate>200502</procdate>
        <srcprod>AMS Topo Digital Raster Graphic</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
              <cntper>GIS Technician</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 9:00 A.M. to 4:00 P.M. EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
      <rowcount>6768</rowcount>
      <colcount>8858</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>47</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>99.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>21.414727</absres>
            <ordres>21.403454</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>This raster image of a topographic maps shows relief, drainage, vegetation, populated places, cultural features, and coastal hydrography.  Maps in this series also show transportation features (roads, railroads, tracks and trails), spot elevations and national and international boundaries.

Map collar information contains an abundance of ancillary data including map legends, grid numbering systems, glossaries of features and places (in English and modified Wade-Giles Romanized Chinese).  Many features are identified by Chinese ideographs as well.</eaover>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>TIFF</formname>
          <filedec>no compression applied</filedec>
          <transize>171.573</transize>
        </digtinfo>
      </digform>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050502</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
          <cntper>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
