<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</origin>
        <pubdate>2014</pubdate>
        <title>Rooftop Solar Panels, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 2010 (pub. 2014)</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Cambridge, MA, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>City of Cambridge IT Department</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-cambridge14rooftopsolarpanels</onlink>
        <lworkcit>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</origin>
            <pubdate>2014</pubdate>
            <title>City of Cambridge MA GIS Data 2014</title>
            <geoform>digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Cambridge, Massachusetts</pubplace>
              <publish>Cambridge (Mass.) Geographic Information Systems</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </lworkcit>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This layer contains line features representing rooftop solar panels in Cambridge, Massachusetts, 2014</abstract>
      <purpose>This layer is intended for researchers, students, and policy makers for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production, or to provide a basemap to support graphical overlays and analysis with other spatial data.</purpose>
      <supplinf>City of Cambridge, MA GIS basemap development project encompasses the land area of City of Cambridge with a 200 foot fringe surrounding the area and Charles River shoreline towards Boston. The basemap data was developed at 1 = 40' mapping scale using digital photogrammetric techniques. Planimetric features; both man-made and natural features like vegetation, rivers have been depicted. These features are important to all GIS/mapping applications and publication. A set of data layers such as Buildings, Roads, Rivers, Utility structures, 1 ft interval contours are developed and represented in the geodatabase. The features are labeled and coded in order to represent specific feature class for thematic representation and topology between the features is maintained for an accurate representation at the 1:40 mapping scale for both publication and analysis. The basemap data has been developed using procedures designed to produce data to the National Standard for Spatial Data Accuracy (NSSDA) and is intended for use at 1 = 40 ' mapping scale.City of Cambridge 1 - 40' base map layers from an April 14, 2010 flyover. Basemap layers created by Infotech America.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2010</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-71.154223</westbc>
        <eastbc>-71.071291</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.399993</northbc>
        <southbc>42.358825</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Solar energy</themekey>
        <themekey>Photovoltaic power generation</themekey>
        <themekey>Solar cells</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>structure</themekey>
        <themekey>utilitiesCommunication</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Planimetric Data</themekey>
        <themekey>Contour</themekey>
        <themekey>Digital Terrain Model (DTM)</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>City of Cambridge, MA</placekey>
        <placekey>USA</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>GNIS</placekt>
        <placekey>Massachusetts</placekey>
        <placekey>Cambridge</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unrestricted Access OnlineThe project data is the property of City of Cambridge, MA and collaborating institutions and licensed with all rights. Distribution of any of these data to anyone not licensed by the by the City of Cambridge, MA is strictly prohibited.</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <datacred>City of Cambridge GIS, Infotech America</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.2.2.3552</native>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>City of Cambridge</cntorg>
          <cntper>Cambridge GIS</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Data</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>831 Massachusetts Ave</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02139</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-349-4140</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>CambridgeGIS@cambridgema.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>The dataset contains vector (planimetric, Topography and Contours) files and raster (Ortho imagery) and LiDAR. The file naming convention of the datasets is based on a Basic Modular Unit of tile grid adopted by the City of Cambridge, MA based on the NAD_1983_StatePlane_Massachusetts_Mainland_FIPS_2001_Feet, and vertical datum is NAVD 1988. The neat area is bounded by the state plane grid whose easting and northing are evenly divisible by 2640 x 2640 feet. Each Basic Modular Unit map is identified by a map number derived from grid naming convention with alphanumeric values. The rows are numbered from South to North and the Columns named with A, B, C, from West to East. E.g. A1, A2, etc.</logic>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Compiled to meet horizontal and vertical accuracy at 95% confidence level in accordance with ASPRS Class 1 standards.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Compiled to meet the vertical accuracy at 95% confidence level in accordance with ASPRS Class 1 standards.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Digital aerial photography was acquired using Microsoft-Vexcel UltraCAMX on April 14, 2010 on a clear day with onboard airborne GPS and IMU parameters. Digital Aerial Triangulation (DAT) was performed, primarily, using softcopy workstations and Intergraph's ISPM / ISAT software or BINGO where applicable. Image tie points were collected using automatic correlation. The correlated points were triangulated and blunders were rectified with manual edits until the desired accuracy levels were achieved. Well distributed 21 ground control points surveyed in the year 2010, 6 controls from 2006_Harvard, 6 controls form 2003_CambridgeGIS and 5 vertical controls from 1995_CambridgeGIS were used to achieve the absolute accuracy within the defined residual limits. Geodatabase schema was developed for the Planimetric features to create the required basemap data. The planimetric features were compiled using standard pothogrammetric collection techniques on Intergraph's SSK softcopy workstations. The features were post processed in ESRI's ArcGIS and topology validation was performed. The dataset comprises of 35 feature classes with 142 attribute domains. Feature specific description is provided in the attributes section of this metadata. Appropriate attributes for the hydro features, buildings, etc were conflated from the Cambridge, MA existing GIS database. Digital Terrain Model (DTM) was developed using softcopy photogrammetry for the purposes of ortho rectification and 1 ft contour generation. Elevation point (masspoint) data was collected at 20ft grid and supplemented with breaklines. Breaklines were collected at significant breaks in the terrain to support the generation of 1 ft interval contours. DTM data was enhanced with the contour interpolate (CIP) 3d geometry features include Curb, Road Paved &amp; Unpaved, Road-Traffic-Island, Alley, Trail Paved &amp; Unpaved, Driveway Paved &amp; Unpaved, Parking lot Paved and Unpaved, Sidewalk, Public Footpath, Impervious features, Concrete Pad, Patio, Plaza and other impervious features, Rail road - Abandon, Active, Elevated, Floodwall, Wet area, Open channel, River / stream, Pond, In ground pool, Retention Pond, Retaining Wall, etc) to generate accurate 1ft contours. Also, spot elevations were collected at street intersections, depression areas, saddles and peaks. These DTM features include elevation points, breaklines, CIP features and spot elevations were interpolated using Maps 3D software and 1 ft contours were generated. Contours were coded for Index (every 5th contour), intermediate, depression, hidden and obscured according to the specification. Index contours were labeled with the contour value. Spot elevations placed at the intersections of streets, ridges, saddles, depressions were labeled with one decimal precision for cartographic representation. DTM data was supplemented with building polygons and used for true ortho generation for the project area. All the Planimetric features, DTM points and Contour data was loaded to Geodabase schema and annotation layers were created for Streets (Roads), Spot Elevations, Cemeteries, Hydro and Index Contours from the respective attribute fields.Topology has been validated for all features.</procdesc>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Infotech Enterprises America, Inc</cntorg>
              <cntper>Srinu Ratnala</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>100 Carpenter Dr, STE 200</address>
              <city>Sterling</city>
              <state>Virginia</state>
              <postal>20164</postal>
              <country>United States of America</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(571) 313-1065 ext 129</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>(571) 313-1071</cntfax>
            <cntemail>Srinu.Ratnala@infotech-enterprises.com</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The data was downloaded from the City of Cambridge GitHub repository (https://github.com/cambridgegis) as geojson files. The files were renamed to flatten the directory structure and add more identifying information. GeoJSON was processed to shapefile format using the GDAL command OGR2OGR with the ?f ?ESRI Shapefile? option and UTF-8 encoding, GDAL version 1.11.1 released 2014/09/24. ArcCatalog 10.1 was utilized to export the shapefile into an ArcSDE 9.3.1 database using the ?Feature Class to Feature Class? export tool.</procdesc>
        <srcused>source vector dataset</srcused>
        <procdate>2014</procdate>
        <srcprod>Shapefile</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Librarian for Geographic Information Services</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Harvard Map Collection</address>
              <address>Pusey Library</address>
              <address>Harvard Yard</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>223</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Rooftop Solar Panels, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 2010 (pub. 2014)</enttypl>
        <enttypd>A structure is man-made free-standing, immobile outdoor construction. Structure features include Storage Tanks (water, fuel, misc), Smokestack, Porch, Deck, Stairs, Swimming Pool in-ground and above-ground, Bus Shelter, Subway head house, Headwall, Wing wall, etc. Outline of the structure is collected as polygon feature.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOP_GL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation of highest point above ground level (NAVD88)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ELEV_SL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation of solar panel edge above sea level (NAVD88)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOP_SL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation of highest point above sea level (NAVD88)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BASE_ELEV</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Base elevation of structure (NAVD88)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>All types are rooftop solar panels</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ELEV_GL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation of solar panel edge above ground level (NAVD88)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Cambridge (Mass.). Geographic Information Systems</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape.area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape.len</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of arc in coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard University Information Technology</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Library Technology Services</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>Although this data is being distributed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Shapefile</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu/</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Web-based distribution only</ordering>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20140613</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Metadata Librarian</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Information Technology</address>
          <address>Library Technology Services</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metsi>
      <metscs>Not Available</metscs>
      <metshd>Not Available</metshd>
    </metsi>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
