<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</origin>
        <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
        <pubdate>20040301</pubdate>
        <title>ESRI Data &amp; Maps 2004 : U.S. ZIP Code Areas (Three-Digit)</title>
        <edition>2004</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
          <issue>2004</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>ESRI</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>Location: ESRI data &amp; maps 2004 \usa\census</othercit>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-esri04uszip3</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>U.S. ZIP Code Areas (Three-Digit) represents the first three digits of a ZIP Code. The first digit of a five-digit ZIP Code divides the country into 10 large groups of states numbered from 0 in the Northeast to 9 in the far West. Within these areas, each state is divided into an average of 10 smaller geographical areas, identified by the 2nd and 3rd digits. These digits, in conjunction with the first digit, represent a sectional center facility or a mail processing facility area. These areas are serviced by the U.S. Post Office Sectional Center Facility (SCF). Note that a single SCF often services multiple three-digit areas.</abstract>
      <purpose>U.S. ZIP Code Areas (Three-Digit) provides area and population for each three-digit ZIP Code area in the United States.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:100,000.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>200311</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>2000</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>200303</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition: 200311, 2000; publication date: 200303</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Matches software update releases</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-178.226727</westbc>
        <eastbc>-66.952936</eastbc>
        <northbc>71.357355</northbc>
        <southbc>18.916073</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Zip codes</themekey>
        <themekey>Postal service</themekey>
        <themekey>Population Statistics</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>location</themekey>
        <themekey>society</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>polygon</themekey>
        <themekey>zip codes</themekey>
        <themekey>areas</themekey>
        <themekey>three-digit zip codes</themekey>
        <themekey>sectional center facility</themekey>
        <themekey>population</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>2003</tempkey>
        <tempkey>2000</tempkey>
        <tempkey>2003</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
    <useconst>The data are provided under the Harvard University Site License.  These data must be used in compliance with the Site License.  This means that the data are only available for Harvard Affiliates for use on Harvard owned computers.  

The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps for use with ESRI software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, "Geodata" shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor for hard-copy renditions or static, electronic map images (e.g. .gif, .jpeg, etc.) that are plotted, printed, or publicly displayed with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).  Geodata is redistributable with a Value-Added Software Application developed by ESRI Business Partners on a royalty-free basis with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).

[Applicable to ESRI Business Information Solutions attribute only]--In addition to the redistribution rights above, geodata is redistributable without a Value-Added Software Application (i.e., adding the sample data to an existing, [non]commercial data set for redistribution) with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).

The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
          <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
        <cntinst>In the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>United States Postal Service</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.0.0.535</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>No duplicate features are present. The shapefile is converted to SDC (Smart Data Compression) format in ArcSDE. This verifies and validates the geometry.</logic>
    <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The geospatial part of this data set was extracted from the 2000 Census TIGER/Line files (CD-ROM edition). To improve the accuracy, GDT ran a process against the entire nationwide database.  It was generalized to 1,000 points per polygon and 4,000 points per feature. Generalizing reduced the positional accuracy and can't be determined.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</origin>
            <pubdate>200401</pubdate>
            <title>Dynamap/2000 v. 14.0</title>
            <edition>Version 14.0</edition>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>Dynamap/2000</sername>
              <issue>Version 14.0</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Lebanon, New Hampshire, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>Geographic Data Technology, Inc</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>200311</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>GDT Dynamap/2000 v. 14.0</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau.</origin>
            <pubdate>2000</pubdate>
            <title>2000 Census of Population and Housing Public Law 94-171</title>
            <edition>2000</edition>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>Census of Population and Housing Public Law 94-171</sername>
              <issue>2000</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>USA</pubplace>
              <publish>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2000</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Census 94-171</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>ESRI Business Information Solutions</origin>
            <pubdate>200303</pubdate>
            <geoform>tabular digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Vienna, Virginia, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>ESRI Business Information Solutions</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Provided POP2003.</othercit>
            <title>ESRI Business Information Solutions data</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>200303</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>ESRI BIS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>How GDT Creates These Files: Creating ZIP Code Areas is a technical process that carefully coordinates United States Postal Service (USPS) postal data and our own Dynamap street data.  The U.S. Post Office assigns ZIP Codes on a street-by-street basis. ZIP code areas are used by the USPS to deliver mail more effectively. Their purpose was never intended to form boundaries for spatial analysis. As a result, GDT formed the following processes to build boundaries from the mail stops present on street segments. By utilizing a wide variety of sources, GDT is able to locate ZIP code changes both large and small and change the representation of ZIP Code areas by redefining the boundaries.

Aligning ZIP Code Zones &amp; Street Segments: The ZIP boundaries are created manually by following actual Dynamap street segments and other non-street features. In areas where the street name match rate is low, GDT technicians make telephone inquiries to area Post Offices, and refer to USPS ZIP+4 State Directories, to determine the predominant ZIP Code. The ZIP Code delivery "zone" is approximated, and ZIP boundaries are created manually by following Dynamap street and non-street segments.

U.S. ZIP Code Areas have been generalized to 1,000 points per polygon and 4,000 points per feature.</procdesc>
        <procdate>200401</procdate>
        <srcprod>GDT Dynamap/2000 v. 14.0</srcprod>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Copied 2004 U.S. ZIP Code Areas and renamed it. Added ZIP3 attribute and summarized on the first 3 characters in the ZIP Code. Summarized AREA, SUMBLKPOP, and POP2003 attributes. Removed -99 values when summarizing POP2003 attribute. Manually fixed 7 features when ZIP Code is in more than one state (given to the largest area state). Corrected 000 and 001 features to be individual features for easier display. Converted the data set to SDC. Created the projection file (.prj) and spatial indices.</procdesc>
        <srcused>GDT Dynamap/2000 v. 14.0</srcused>
        <srcused>Census 94-171</srcused>
        <srcused>ESRI BIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20040315</procdate>
        <srcprod>SDC</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
              <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>380 New York Street</address>
              <city>Redlands</city>
              <state>California</state>
              <postal>92373-8100</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
            <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
            <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>In the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>This layer was originally downloaded from the ESRI Data and Maps 2004 DVD.  The file was stored in SDC (Smart Data Compression) format on the DVD.  ArcCatalog 9.1was utilized to export the SDC file to a shapefile and then loaded into an ArcSDE 9.1 database using the command line importing tool "SHP2SDE".   Any shapes that were rejected due to bad geometry were fixed with the "Repair Geometry" tool in ArcCatalog.  These shapes were then appended to the ArcSDE layer using the SDE command line tool "SHP2SDE append".</procdesc>
        <srcused>SDC</srcused>
        <procdate>20060314</procdate>
        <srcprod>Shape</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>3289</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>ESRI04USZIP3</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The polygons represent areas serviced by sectional center facilities or mail processing facilities within United States.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP2003</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The 2003 estimated population of the ZIP Code area.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI Business Information Solutions</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Populations for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-99</edomv>
            <edomvd>Data not available.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ZIP3</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The three-digit number used by the postal service to identify an area serviced by a sectional center facility or mail processing facility.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>United States Postal Service</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>USPS National 5-Digit ZIP and Post Office Directory</codesetn>
            <codesets>United States Postal Service</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The two-letter abbreviation for the state in which the ZIP Code area is located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>United States Postal Service</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>USPS City/State File</codesetn>
            <codesets>United States Postal Service</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ESRI04USZIP3.AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The area of the ZIP Code polygon in square miles using Albers Equal Area Projection.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Calculated areas for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ESRI04USZIP3.FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SUMBLKPOP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The sum of the 2000 population for the Census Bureau Block polygon centroids which fall within the zip code area.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI; Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Summed populations for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in square coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of arc in coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard University Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>See use constraints.  Although this data is being distributed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>SHAPE</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Web-based distribution only.</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports ArcView(r) GIS shapefiles.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
    <metd>20060920</metd>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
