<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>DMTI Spatial Inc.</origin>
        <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
        <pubdate>20040301</pubdate>
        <title>ESRI Data &amp; Maps 2004 : Canada Municipalities</title>
        <edition>2004</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
          <issue>2004</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>ESRI</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>Location: ESRI data &amp; maps 2004 \canada</othercit>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-esri04canmunicp</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Canada Municipalities represents the municipalities within Canada of types including cities, cantons, hamlets, towns/ville, villages, Indian reserves, parishes/paroisse, communities, unorganized, districts, and terre Inuite. The boundaries are digitized from CanMap.</abstract>
      <purpose>Canada Municipalities provides the municipalities of Canada with detail appropriate for national, regional, and local levels.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:50,000.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>200209</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1996</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Matches software update releases</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-141.002118</westbc>
        <eastbc>-52.619173</eastbc>
        <northbc>83.115063</northbc>
        <southbc>41.687973</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Cities and towns</themekey>
        <themekey>Municipal government</themekey>
        <themekey>Villages</themekey>
        <themekey>Indian reservations</themekey>
        <themekey>Human settlements</themekey>
        <themekey>Boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>Administrative and political boundaries</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>polygon</themekey>
        <themekey>municipalities</themekey>
        <themekey>cities</themekey>
        <themekey>cantons</themekey>
        <themekey>hamlets</themekey>
        <themekey>towns/ville</themekey>
        <themekey>parishes/paroisse</themekey>
        <themekey>communities</themekey>
        <themekey>districts</themekey>
        <themekey>terre Inuite</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>Canada</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>2002</tempkey>
        <tempkey>1996</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
    <useconst>The data are provided under the Harvard University Site License.  These data must be used in compliance with the Site License.  This means that the data are only available for Harvard Affiliates for use on Harvard owned computers.  

The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps for use with ESRI software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, "Geodata" shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor for hard-copy renditions or static, electronic map images (e.g. .gif, .jpeg, etc.) that are plotted, printed, or publicly displayed with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).  Geodata is redistributable with a Value-Added Software Application developed by ESRI Business Partners on a royalty-free basis with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).

The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
          <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
        <cntinst>In the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.3.0.800</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>No duplicate features are present. The shapefile is converted to SDC (Smart Data Compression) format in ArcSDE. This verifies and validates the geometry.</logic>
    <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The positional accuracy ranges from sub-meter (GPS derived) to 5 meters (1:50,000 National Topographic Data Base (NTDB) areas) or greater, in the case of Northern areas in Canada not covered by NTDB, namely, most of Nunavut, much of Northwest Territories and northern parts of British Columbia, Alberta, Manitoba, Ontario and Quebec.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>DMTI Spatial Inc.</origin>
            <pubdate>200209</pubdate>
            <title>Canadian Data Bundle-Data sets from CanMap with source scales of 1:2000 to 1:50,000.</title>
            <edition>2002</edition>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>Canadian Data Bundle</sername>
              <issue>2002</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Markham, Ontario, Canada</pubplace>
              <publish>DMTI Spatial Inc.</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>2000-50000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>200209</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>1996</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>DMTI Spatial Inc. - 2 to 50</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The data set is a fully georeferenced, purely digital product. The boundaries are digitized from CanMap. Source data ranges from municipal mapping at a very large scale of 1:2,000 or larger, to a medium scale of 1:50,000 scale from NTDB*.  Source time period of content ranges from a few to several years (as in the case of NTDB*).
 
*NTDB is the National Topographic Data Base, developed and maintained by Natural Resources Canada.</procdesc>
        <procdate>200209</procdate>
        <srcprod>DMTI Spatial Inc. - 2 to 50</srcprod>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Extracted data set from DMTI Spatial Canadian Data Bundle. Removed erroneous island at 80 N 135 W. Removed erroneous sliver polygons in the ocean. Renamed POP96 and DWELL96 attributes to POP1996 and DWELL1996 respectively. Created ArcGIS layer file (.lyr), projection file (.prj), and spatial indices. Converted the data set to SDC.</procdesc>
        <srcused>DMTI Spatial Inc. - 2 to 50</srcused>
        <procdate>20021001</procdate>
        <srcprod>SDC</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
              <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>380 New York Street</address>
              <city>Redlands</city>
              <state>California</state>
              <postal>92373-8100</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
            <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
            <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>In the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Added SQKM attribute and calculated its values. Made NAME attribute title case.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20040305</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
              <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>380 New York Street</address>
              <city>Redlands</city>
              <state>California</state>
              <postal>92373-8100</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
            <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
            <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>In the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>This layer was originally downloaded from the ESRI Data and Maps 2004 DVD.  The file was stored in an SDC (Smart Data Compression) format on the DVD.  ArcCatalog 9.1 was utilized to export the SDC file to a shapefile, and then the "Repair Geometry" tool was used to correct geometric discrepancies that would otherwise have prevented a given line or polygon from being imported to Arc SDE.  After the "Repair Geometry" tool was run, the file was exported from ArcCatalog 9.1 to an ArcSDE 9.1 database, using the "Feature Class to Feature Class" export tool.</procdesc>
        <srcused>SDC</srcused>
        <procdate>20060309</procdate>
        <srcprod>Shape</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>5984</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>ESRI04CANMUNICP</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The polygons represent the municipal political units for Canada.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PROV</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The two-letter abbreviation for the province or territory in which the municipality is located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>DMTI Spatial Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>AB</edomv>
            <edomvd>Alberta</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>BC</edomv>
            <edomvd>British Columbia</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>MB</edomv>
            <edomvd>Manitoba</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NB</edomv>
            <edomvd>New Brunswick</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NF</edomv>
            <edomvd>Newfoundland and Labrador</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NS</edomv>
            <edomvd>Nova Scotia</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NT</edomv>
            <edomvd>Northwest Territories</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NU</edomv>
            <edomvd>Nunavut</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>ON</edomv>
            <edomvd>Ontario</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>PE</edomv>
            <edomvd>Prince Edward Island</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>QC</edomv>
            <edomvd>Quebec</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SK</edomv>
            <edomvd>Saskatchewan</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>YT</edomv>
            <edomvd>Yukon Territory</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Canada Post Corporation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The municipality name.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>DMTI Spatial Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Names for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The type of municipality.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>DMTI Spatial Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Borough.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>C</edomv>
            <edomvd>City.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>CC</edomv>
            <edomvd>Chartered Community.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>CM</edomv>
            <edomvd>County.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>COM</edomv>
            <edomvd>Community.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>CT</edomv>
            <edomvd>Canton.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>CU</edomv>
            <edomvd>Cantons Unis.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>DM</edomv>
            <edomvd>District Municipality.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>HAM</edomv>
            <edomvd>Hamlet.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>ID</edomv>
            <edomvd>Improvement District.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>IGD</edomv>
            <edomvd>Indian Government District.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>LGD</edomv>
            <edomvd>Local Government District.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>LOT</edomv>
            <edomvd>Township and Royalty.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>M</edomv>
            <edomvd>Municipality.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>MD</edomv>
            <edomvd>Municipality District.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NH</edomv>
            <edomvd>Northern Hamlet.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NT</edomv>
            <edomvd>Northern Town.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NV</edomv>
            <edomvd>Northern Village.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>P</edomv>
            <edomvd>Paroisse.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>PAR</edomv>
            <edomvd>Parish.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>R</edomv>
            <edomvd>Indian Reserve.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>RC</edomv>
            <edomvd>Rural Community.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>RGM</edomv>
            <edomvd>Regional Municipality.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>RM</edomv>
            <edomvd>Rural Municipality.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>RV</edomv>
            <edomvd>Resort Village.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>S-E</edomv>
            <edomvd>Indian Settlement.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SA</edomv>
            <edomvd>Special Area.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SCM</edomv>
            <edomvd>Subdivision of County Municipality.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SET</edomv>
            <edomvd>Settlement.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SM</edomv>
            <edomvd>Specialized Municipality.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SRD</edomv>
            <edomvd>Subdivision of Regional District.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SUN</edomv>
            <edomvd>Subdivision of Unorganized.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SV</edomv>
            <edomvd>Summer Village.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>T</edomv>
            <edomvd>Town.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>TI</edomv>
            <edomvd>Terre Inuite.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>TP</edomv>
            <edomvd>Township.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>TR</edomv>
            <edomvd>Terres Reservees.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>UNO</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unorganized.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>V</edomv>
            <edomvd>Ville.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>VC</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village Cri.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>VK</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village Naskapi.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>VL</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>VN</edomv>
            <edomvd>Village Nordique.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>DMTI Spatial Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1996</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The 1996 population of the municipality.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>DMTI Spatial Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DWELL1996</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The 1996 dwelling counts of the municipality.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>DMTI Spatial Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHORE_AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The land area of the municipality in square kilometers (not including any part of the municipality covered by water) using a Robinson projection.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>DMTI Spatial Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in square coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of arc in coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SQKM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The measure of area in square kilometers.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Calculated area for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard University Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>See use constraints.  Although this data is being distributed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>SHAPE</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Web-based distribution only.</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports ArcView(r) GIS shapefiles.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20060824</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
