<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Harvard Geospatial Library</origin>
        <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</origin>
        <pubdate>20001101</pubdate>
        <title>U.S. National Atlas Federal and Indian Land Areas</title>
        <edition>2000</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
          <issue>2000</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>Location: ESRI Data &amp; Maps 2000 (CD 2) \usa</othercit>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-esriusfedlandp</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>U.S. National Atlas Federal and Indian Land Areas represents the federal and Indian owned land areas (e.g., Bureau of Indian Affairs, Department of Defense, and Tennessee Valley Authority) of the United States.</abstract>
      <purpose>U.S. National Atlas Federal and Indian Land Areas provides the federal and Indian owned land areas for geographic display and analysis at regional and national levels.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:1,000,000.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1972-1998</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1970-1995</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-179.133392</westbc>
        <eastbc>179.788208</eastbc>
        <northbc>71.340698</northbc>
        <southbc>19.166132</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>polygon</themekey>
        <themekey>federal lands</themekey>
        <themekey>Indian lands</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>1972-1998</tempkey>
        <tempkey>1970-1995</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
    <useconst>The data are provided under the Harvard University Site License.  These data must be used in compliance with the Site License.  This means that the data are only available for Harvard Afiliates for use on Harvard owned computers.  The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD-ROMs for use with ESRI(r) software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD-ROMs. As used herein, "Geodata" shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.  The redistribution rights for this data set: Public domain data from U.S. government is freely redistributable with proper metadata and source attribution.  The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on the ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD-ROMs.  Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.  Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.  THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.  EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.  IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.  Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.  In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</cntorg>
          <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
        <cntinst>In the United States- Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded.   Outside the United States- Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.    For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Windows NT Version 5.0 (Build 2195) ; ESRI ArcInfo 8.1.0.515</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>No duplicate features are present.  The shapefile is exported using Avenue request ExportClean.  This request verifies and enforces the correctness of shapes.</logic>
    <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials. Data completeness generally reflects the content of the original Digital Line Graph (DLG) files.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The geospatial part of this data set was originally extracted from the individual 1:2,000,000-scale State boundary Digital Line Graph (DLG) files produced by the U.S. Geological Survey which have a positional accuracy of 1,720 meters.  It was updated several times using various sources whose horizontal positional accuracies are unknown.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>19980520</pubdate>
            <title>nationalatlas.gov(tm) -Federal and Indian Lands</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <serinfo/>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, Virginia, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>United States Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>http://www.nationalatlas.gov/atlasftp.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>2000000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1970</begdate>
              <enddate>1995</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>National Atlas</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>This file was originally digitized by the National Mapping Division based on the sectional maps contained in 'The National Atlas of the United States of America' published by the USGS in 1970.  The sectional maps were updated during 1978-1981 and digitized in the early 1980's. The data were updated in 1995 using 1:1,000,000-scale and 1:2,000,000-scale Bureau of Land Management state base maps.  These data were published on CD-ROM in 1995.  Using ARC/INFO software, the DLG optional format files were converted to ARC/INFO coverages using the DLGARC command. Only federal land polygons and attribute information were extracted for inclusion.  The sections were then paneled together using the ARC/INFO command APPEND.  "Slivers" created during the append process were identified and deleted using the ELIMINATE command.  The attribute AGBUR was added for plotting purposes. The codes used are: BIA (Bureau of Indian Affairs), BOR (Bureau of Reclamation), BLM (Bureau of Land Management), DOD (Department of Defense), FS (Forest Service), FWS (Fish and Wildlife Service), NPS (National Park Service), TVA (Tennessee Valley Authority), and OTHER.  In 1998, topological errors introduced when the state files were paneled were corrected.  Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument was added.  Coding of Lake Tahoe was corrected, and Fort Frederica, GA was deleted because it was smaller than the minimum area of 640 acres.  The data were converted to shapefile format for use in National Atlas applications and for distribution to the public.  One or more of the following methods tested accuracy at the DLG level: - Manual comparison of the source with hard copy plots. - Symbolized display of the digital line graph (DLG) on an interactive computer graphic system. - Selected attributes that could not be visually verified on plots or on screen were interactively queried and verified on screen.  As the DLG files were directly converted to ARC/INFO coverages, attributes have not been checked in the ARC/INFO format. - The files underwent comparison to a graphic source or image source that was used as control to assess digital positional accuracy.  During conversion to ARC/INFO coverage format and during the append process to panel the states together, node snapping and fuzzy tolerances may have caused minimal positional shifts.  Revisions: 1) 3/22/98 - Corrected topological problems along state lines, corrected coding errors (Lake Tahoe), and added Escalante national monument.  State attribute codes were removed.  Fort Frederica, GA was deleted because it was below the minimum mapping area of 640 acres. 2) 6/17/98 - Corrected URL for Glacier National Park. 3) 6/29/98 - Corrected ellipsoid name from WGS84 to GRS1980 and changed flattening ratio.</procdesc>
        <procdate>19980629</procdate>
        <srcprod>National Atlas</srcprod>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Downloaded the ArcView Shapefile version of the data, fedlanp020.tar.gz, from http://www.nationalatlas.gov/atlasftp.html and extracted it.  Removed null records.  Aggregated features based on all attributes.  Removed unneeded fields.  Created ArcGIS(tm) layer file (.lyr).  Created ArcView legend file (.avl).  Created projection file (.prj).  Ran ArcView Avenue request ExportClean, and created spatial indices.</procdesc>
        <srcused>National Atlas</srcused>
        <procdate>20000804</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Source shape files were loaded into SDE using the shp2sde command by the HGL team.  Spatial reference options -180,-90,1000000.</procdesc>
        <srcused>GDT Dynamap/2000 v7.3</srcused>
        <procdate>20010715</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>3314</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>fedlandp</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The polygons represent the federal and Indian owned lands of 640 acres or more within United States.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FEATURE1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The primary federal agency/bureau.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Boundary layer attribute codes</codesetn>
            <codesets>U.S. GeoData Data Users Guide 3</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FEATURE2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The secondary federal agency/bureau.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Boundary layer attribute codes</codesetn>
            <codesets>U.S. GeoData Data Users Guide 3</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FEATURE3</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The tertiary federal agency/bureau.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Boundary layer attribute codes</codesetn>
            <codesets>U.S. GeoData Data Users Guide 3</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AGBUR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The agency/bureau code.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>BIA</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>BLM</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by the Bureau of Land Management.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>BOR</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by the Bureau of Reclamation.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>DOD</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by the Department of Defense.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FS</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by the U.S. Forest Service.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FWS</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NPS</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by the National Park Service.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>TVA</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by the Tennessee Valley Authority.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>OTHER</edomv>
            <edomvd>Area managed by some other federal agency/bureau.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The primary name of the federal land.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Boundary layer attribute codes</codesetn>
            <codesets>U.S. GeoData Data Users Guide 3</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The secondary name of the federal land.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Boundary layer attribute codes</codesetn>
            <codesets>U.S. GeoData Data Users Guide 3</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME3</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The tertiary name of the federal land.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Boundary layer attribute codes</codesetn>
            <codesets>U.S. GeoData Data Users Guide 3</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The two-letter abbreviation for each state in which the federal land is located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards 5-2</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATE_FIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The FIPS code (two-digit number) for each state in which the federal land is located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>OIS</address>
          <address>1280 Mass Ave</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>See use constraints.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>SHP</formname>
          <filedec>Downloaded file is Zipped</filedec>
          <transize>16.706</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>hgl.harvard.edu</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports ArcView(r) GIS shapefiles.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20001028</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>OIS</address>
          <address>1280 Mass Ave</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
