<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</origin>
        <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
        <pubdate>20050401</pubdate>
        <title>ESRI Data &amp; Maps 2005 : Europe NUTS 2 Demographics</title>
        <edition>2005</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
          <issue>2005</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>ESRI</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>Location: ESRI data &amp; maps 2005 \europe\demography</othercit>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-esri05eurnuts2</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Europe NUTS 2 Demographics represents aggregated socio-economic and demographic information at the NUTS 2 level. NUTS 2 units have a population between 800,000 and 3,000,000 people.

NUTS (Nomenclature des Unites Territoriales Statistiques) refers to the Nomenclature of Territorial Units for Statistics. For more information: http://europa.eu.int/comm/eurostat/ramon/nuts/introduction_regions_en.html.</abstract>
      <purpose>Europe NUTS 2 Demographics provides NUTS 2 level demographic information for Europe.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:200,000.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>2004</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>200503</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Matches software update releases</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-31.268789</westbc>
        <eastbc>68.716100</eastbc>
        <northbc>81.860200</northbc>
        <southbc>27.635003</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Demography</themekey>
        <themekey>Population Statistics</themekey>
        <themekey>Sex Statistics</themekey>
        <themekey>Age distribution (Demography)</themekey>
        <themekey>Households</themekey>
        <themekey>Gross domestic product</themekey>
        <themekey>Boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>Administrative and political divisions</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>society</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>polygon</themekey>
        <themekey>countries</themekey>
        <themekey>demographics</themekey>
        <themekey>NUTS</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>Europe</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>2004</tempkey>
        <tempkey>2005</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
    <useconst>The data are provided under the Harvard University Site License.  These data must be used in compliance with the Site License.  This means that the data are only available for Harvard Affiliates for use on Harvard owned computers.  The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps for use with ESRI software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, "Geodata" shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor for hard-copy renditions or static, electronic map images (for example, .gif, .jpeg,) that are plotted, printed, or publicly displayed with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).

[Applicable to AND International Publishers N.V. only]-Internal Use Only. No redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor and the data is for the end user's own internal use only.


[Applicable to EuroGeographics only]-

End User Licence Agreement

between 
 		
EuroGeographics Association,
6-8, Avenue Blaise Pascal, Cite Descartes, Champs-sur-Marne, F-77455 Marne-la-Vallee Cedex 2, France
Registration No. 435 131 842 00013
VAT No. FR 9343513184200013
Hereinafter referred to as the
EuroGeographics	

And

Licensee of Data &amp; Maps
Hereinafter referred to as the
End User

E1		Definitions
End User is a single person, company or otherwise recognisable legal body who will have usage rights to SABE, as supplied by ESRI within the their Data &amp; Maps cd-rom.
Security Copy is a copy taken solely for the purpose of protecting against accidental loss or corruption.
Product is SABE. SABE is an acronym for ?Seamless Administrative Boundaries of Europe? being a European wide structured digital geographic data base, derived from source data provided by the National Mapping Agencies of Europe.
Reproduction includes any kind of reproduction of SABE in any type or form, whether direct or indirect, permanent or intermediate, in analogue or digital form. It includes reproduction of value-added and derived products.
Communication to the public includes distribution of physical products, and distribution by any other means or process, including wireless communication and broadcasting. It includes all instances of making accessible to the public, whether it is actually accessed or not.
Usage rights are the rights to use for personal (if acquired by a person) or internal (if required by a legal person) use as defined in section E4. Employees shall not be entitled to usage rights for private purposes.

E2		Intellectual Property and Reservation of Ownership
SABE is the intellectual property of the National Mapping Authorities providing information for it. All reproductions of SABE must carry the acknowledgement as specified in section E3. All unauthorised reproduction and distribution infringe this joint property right and could lead to legal action. This Agreement does not transfer any rights except what is clearly stated in the Agreement.

E3	Copyright and Trademark Acknowledgement Note
Pursuant to the ?Yes 1? classification in the Redistribution Rights Matrix, End User must show the appropriate copyright acknowledgement as detailed below on any hard copy renditions or static, electronic map images derived from SABE. The acknowledgement that must be clearly shown is:

SABE includes data licensed from European National Mapping and Cadastral Agencies, 
? EuroGeographics

Or in case of insufficient space:

? EuroGeographics

Any use of the name EuroGeographics and any other trademark registered to, or claimed by, EuroGeographics must show the appropriate trademark notation and an appropriate trade mark acknowledgement note must be shown somewhere on the document. This note may be omitted on very small items where there is insufficient room but the trademark notations must always be shown.

E4		Grant of Rights to End Users
The End User acquires unlimited internal usage rights to SABE on the following conditions:
?	SABE may be installed on an unlimited number of personal computers or workstations within End User?s organisation.
?	The End User is authorised to make SABE or images derived from SABE available for viewing by the public in raster format on the domain address www.XXX of their World-Wide Web server and Intranet server only. Any presentation of SABE (on screen or printed) must carry the acknowledgement as specified in section E3 (three).
?	The End User acknowledges that the Intellectual Property Rights in and to SABE and any trademarks or service marks relating thereto remain the property of the EuroGeographics and its suppliers.
?	The End User is authorised to use reproductions of SABE for reports and within presentations.
?	The End User can make a security copy of the SABE data, taking all reasonable precautions to ensure that the SABE product held on its premises is physically secure.

E5	Restrictions 
?	At no stage will either the vector files of SABE or the vector files derived from SABE be made accessible to Internet users or to any other users outside of the End User organisation.
?	SABE may not be used to provide a bureau service for others or for the benefit of or on behalf of others. 
?	SABE may not be used for any commercial activities other than stated in clause E4 (four), including commercial web services, unless the End User has a signed marketing rights agreement for SABE with EuroGeographics.
?	The End User may not sell or onward sell the SABE product.

E6		Disclaimer of Warranty, Limitation of Liability, and Exclusive Remedy
The nature of SABE is such that EuroGeographics cannot warrant the accuracy of SABE. SABE is provided ?AS-IS? without warranty of any kind.  EuroGeographics and any of the National Mapping and Cadastral Agencies are not inviting reliance on this Data, and End User should always verify actual Data.

EUROGEOGRAPHICS AND ANY OF THE NATIONAL MAPPING AND CADASTRAL AGENCIES DISCLAIM ALL OTHER WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, AND NONINFRINGEMENT. EUROGEOGRAPHICS DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET END USER?S NEEDS, OR THAT END USER?S OPERATION OF THE SAME WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR FREE, OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED.

IN NO EVENT SHALL EUROGEOGRAPHICS AND ANY OF THE NATIONAL MAPPING AND CADASTRAL AGENCIES BE LIABLE TO END USER FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS; LOST SALES OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES; INVESTMENTS; OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS, LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL, OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO THIS LICENSE AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA OR DOCUMENTATION, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT EUROGEOGRAPHICS AND ANY OF THE NATIONAL MAPPING AND CADASTRAL AGENCIES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY LIMITED REMEDY.

The End User agrees that EuroGeographics? sole liability and the End Users sole remedy in respect of any breach of Agreement shall be for EuroGeographics to replace the SABE product.

E7 		Indemnity
The End User shall keep harmless and indemnify EuroGeographics against all claims, actions, suits, damages, liabilities, losses, charges and proceedings that EuroGeographics may incur or be put to as a direct result of any breach of this Agreement by the End User or its contractors.

E8	Dispute Resolution
Before resorting to any external dispute resolution mechanism, the Parties shall attempt to settle by negotiation any dispute in relation to this Agreement. The Parties can decide to use a third person or institution as mediator in their negotiations. The Parties decide to what extent the mediator?s decisions will be binding. Disputes shall be handled by the courts of France or by arbitration if both Parties agree to it. 

E9	Governing Law, Interpretation
This Agreement shall be interpreted in all respects according to general principles of international contract law, as reflected in the UNIDROIT Principles of International Commercial Contracts, and be governed according to the law of France. Only the English language version of this Agreement shall be considered enforceable.


The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
          <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
        <cntinst>In the United States-
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States-
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.1.0.722</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>No duplicate features are present. The shapefile is converted to SDC (Smart Data Compression) format in ArcSDE. This verifies and validates the geometry.</logic>
    <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The positional accuracy is unknown.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</origin>
            <origin>EuroGeographics</origin>
            <pubdate>200503</pubdate>
            <title>[Custom package for ESRI Data &amp; Maps 2005]</title>
            <geoform>tabular digital data and vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Nurnberg, Germany; Champs-sur-Marne, France</pubplace>
              <publish>Michael Bauer Research GmbH; EuroGeographics</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Michael Bauer Research GmbH provided all attribute data.

EuroGeographics was the primary source for the boundary data.

The custom package included:
MBR - Economic and Sociodemographic Data for Europe, EuroGeographics boundary data, NUTS 0, NUTS 1, NUTS 2 and NUTS 3 attribute tables, and correspondence tables-AND Data to NUTS and NUTS 3 to NUTS 0, NUTS 1, NUTS 2.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.mb-research.de</onlink>
            <onlink>http://www.eurogeographics.org/eng/04_sabe.asp</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000 [EuroGeographics]</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>200503</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>MBR and EuroGeographics</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>AND International Publishers N.V.</origin>
            <pubdate>2004</pubdate>
            <title>AND Global Road Data</title>
            <edition>2004-H2</edition>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>AND Global Road Data</sername>
              <issue>2004-H2</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Rotterdam, The Netherlands</pubplace>
              <publish>AND International Publishers N.V.</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Provided mapping boundaries for European countries that were not covered by the EuroGeographics data set.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.and.com</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>200000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2004</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>AND Global Road Data</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Michael Bauer Research GmbH established the data by reviewing relevant regional data and projecting the respective trends. For providing the best possible value to the user regarding comparability, all country results were projected by mathematical methods to the required geographical level, homogeneous base years, categories (for example, age bands) and currency (Euro).

Other remarks:
For Azerbaijan, Georgia, and Vatican City only population and population density are surveyed.
For Andorra, Gibraltar, Liechtenstein, Monaco, and San Marino the number of dwellings is not surveyed.
In Russia, only the European part of the country is surveyed (in accordance with the maps).

Michael Bauer Research GmbH research provided ESRI with:
MBR - Economic and Sociodemographic Data for Europe, EuroGeographics boundary data, NUTS 0, NUTS 1, NUTS 2 and NUTS 3 attribute tables, and correspondence tables--AND Data to NUTS and NUTS 3 to NUTS 0, NUTS 1, NUTS 2.</procdesc>
        <procdate>2005</procdate>
        <srcprod>MBR and EuroGeographics</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
              <address>Further Str. 27</address>
              <city>Nurnberg</city>
              <postal>90429</postal>
              <country>Germany</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>+49 (0) 911 / 28 707 020</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>+49 (0) 911 / 28 707 077</cntfax>
            <cntemail>info@mb-research.de</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Edgematched together EuroGeographics boundary data and AND Global Road Data giving precedence to EuroGeographics data (the data was kept as two data sets). Joined each data set to its respective correspondence table to get NUTS 0, NUTS 1, NUTS 2, and NUTS 3 codes into each data set. Added the BND_SOURCE attribute to both data sets populating it in the EuroGeographics boundary data with "EuroGeographics" and in the AND Global Road Data with "AND Data Solutions".

Combined the two data sets into one. Went through the NUTS 1, NUTS 2, and NUTS 3 codes for each country and changed the code to its NUTS 0 code if that country had no lower levels. For example, if all NUTS 2 codes for Danmark were "DK00", then they were changed to "DK". If a country didn't have data for a particular level of NUTS, then all records for that country got the NUTS 0 code for that level.

Dissolved the data set into four data sets of NUTS 0, NUTS 1, NUTS 2, and NUTS 3 and corrected any problems. Joined the attribute data from Michael Bauer Research GmbH to each of the four data sets.

For data sets NUTS 1, NUTS 2, and NUTS 3, put "-99" values into the number attributes and blank values into the PP_CATEGOR and PP_INCNTRY attributes for all records with a NUTS 0 code, since there was no data for that level. Due to a lack of boundary information, five NUTS units couldn't be subdivided into the next lower level. 

Added the SQKM attribute to each of the four data sets and calculated its values. Finalized the attribute names, widths, and order in each data set. Created ArcGIS layer file (.lyr), projection file (.prj), and spatial indices for each data set.</procdesc>
        <srcused>MBR and EuroGeographics</srcused>
        <srcused>AND Global Road Data</srcused>
        <procdate>20050329</procdate>
        <srcprod>SDC</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
              <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>380 New York Street</address>
              <city>Redlands</city>
              <state>California</state>
              <postal>92373-8100</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
            <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
            <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>In the United States-
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States-
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>This layer was originally downloaded from the ESRI Data and Maps 2005 DVD.  The file was stored in an SDC (Smart Data Compression) format on the DVD.  ArcCatalog 9.2 was utilized to export the SDC file into an ArcSDE 9.1 database using the "Feature Class to Feature Class" export tool.</procdesc>
        <srcused>SDC</srcused>
        <procdate>200704</procdate>
        <srcprod>Shape</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>383</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>ESRI05EURNUTS2</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The polygons represent aggregated socio-economic and demographic information at the NUTS 2 level for Europe.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>ESRI</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NUTS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The NUTS 2 code or the NUTS 0 code if there are no NUTS 2 geographical units for this country.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Nomenclature of Territorial Units for Statistics (NUTS)</codesetn>
            <codesets>Regulation of the European Parliament and of the Council on the establishment of a common classification of territorial units for statistics (NUTS)</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The name of the NUTS geographical unit.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Names for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NUTS0</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The NUTS 0 code for the country the NUTS graphical unit is in.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Nomenclature of Territorial Units for Statistics (NUTS)</codesetn>
            <codesets>Regulation of the European Parliament and of the Council on the establishment of a common classification of territorial units for statistics (NUTS)</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POPULATION</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The population of the NUTS geographical unit, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MALES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of males, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FEMALES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of females, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HOUSEHOLDS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of households, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERS_HH</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The average number of persons per household, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP_DENSIT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The population per square kilometer, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Calculated populations per square kilometer for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DWELLINGS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of dwellings, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AGE_0_14</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of people 0 to 14 years of age, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AGE_15_29</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of people 15 to 29 years of age, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AGE_30_44</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of people 30 to 44 years of age, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AGE_45_59</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of people 45 to 59 years of age, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AGE_60_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of people 60 years of age and over, 2004 year average.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PP_CATEGOR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The yearly amount of purchasing power (i.e. disposable income) in Euro per capita, 2004.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>below 1,250</edomv>
            <edomvd>Below 1,250 Euro.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1,250 - 2,499</edomv>
            <edomvd>1,250 to 2,499 Euro.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2,500 - 4,999</edomv>
            <edomvd>2,500 to 4,999 Euro.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>5,000 - 9,999</edomv>
            <edomvd>5,000 to 9,999 Euro.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>10,000 - 14,999</edomv>
            <edomvd>10,000 to 14,999 Euro.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>15,000 - 19,999</edomv>
            <edomvd>15,000 to 19,999 Euro.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>20,000 and more</edomv>
            <edomvd>20,000 Euro and above.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PP_INCNTRY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The yearly amount of purchasing power (i.e. disposable income) in Euro per capita, 2004.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Rank categories based on the range of values that occur within each country for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GDP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The Gross Domestic Product in millions of Euro, 2003.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Michael Bauer Research GmbH</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BND_SOURCE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The indicator for the source of the boundaries.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>AND Data Solutions</edomv>
            <edomvd>The source of the boundaries is AND Data Solutions.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>EuroGeographics</edomv>
            <edomvd>The source of the boundaries is EuroGeographics.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SQKM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The area of the NUTS geographical unit in square kilometers.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Calculated areas for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in square coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of arc in coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>See use constraints.  Although this data is being distributed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Shapefile</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Web-based distribution only.</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports ArcView(r) GIS shapefiles.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20070427</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
