<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Geological Survey (U.S.)</origin>
        <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
        <pubdate>20090601</pubdate>
        <title>U.S. Geographic Names Information System Locales : ESRI Data &amp; Maps 2009</title>
        <edition>2009 Data Update</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
          <issue>2009 Data Update - World, Europe, United States, and Mexico</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>ESRI</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>Location: ESRI data &amp; maps 2009 \usa\landmarks</othercit>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-esri09usglocale</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>U.S. Geographic Names Information System Locales represents an automated inventory of the proper names and locations of physical and cultural geographic features located throughout the United States and its Territories.</abstract>
      <purpose>Geographic Names Information System (GNIS), of which U.S. Geographic Names Information System Locales is a part, promotes geographic feature name standardization and serves as the Federal Government's repository of information regarding feature name spellings and applications for features in United States and its Territories. The names listed in the inventory can be published on Federal maps, charts, and in other documents.  The feature locative information has been used in emergency preparedness, marketing, site-selection and analysis, genealogical and historical research, and transportation routing applications.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:24,000.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>19810501</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>20080128</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1974-Present</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>200802</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date: 19810501, 20080128, 200802; ground condition: 1974-Present</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Annually</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-176.813333</westbc>
        <eastbc>179.288938</eastbc>
        <northbc>71.385144</northbc>
        <southbc>-14.329167</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Names, Geographical</themekey>
        <themekey>Recreation areas</themekey>
        <themekey>Shopping centers</themekey>
        <themekey>Buildings</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>location</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>point</themekey>
        <themekey>locale</themekey>
        <themekey>place name</themekey>
        <themekey>elevation</themekey>
        <themekey>geographic feature</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekey>Puerto Rico</placekey>
        <placekey>Virgin Islands of the United States</placekey>
        <placekey>Guam</placekey>
        <placekey>Micronesia (Federated States)</placekey>
        <placekey>Palau</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall Islands</placekey>
        <placekey>American Samoa</placekey>
        <placekey>Northern Mariana Islands</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>U.S. Commonwealths</placekey>
        <placekey>U.S. Territories</placekey>
        <placekey>U.S. Freely Associated States</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>1981</tempkey>
        <tempkey>2008</tempkey>
        <tempkey>1974-Present</tempkey>
        <tempkey>2008</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
    <useconst>The data are provided under the Harvard University Site License.  These data must be used in compliance with the Site License.  This means that the data are only  available for Harvard Affiliates for use on Harvard owned computers.

The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps for use with ESRI software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, "Geodata" shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Public domain data from U.S. government is freely redistributable with proper metadata and source attribution.

The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES: 
(A) THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE NOT FAULT-TOLERANT AND ARE NOT DESIGNED, MANUFACTURED, OR INTENDED FOR USE OR RESALE FOR INSURANCE UNDERWRITING OR WITH CRITICAL HEALTH AND SAFETY OR ONLINE CONTROL EQUIPMENT IN HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS THAT REQUIRE FAIL-SAFE PERFORMANCE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE OPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES, NAVIGATION OR GUIDANCE (I.E., AIRCRAFT, NAUTICAL VEHICLE, ETC.), OR COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL, EMERGENCY RESPONSE, TERRORISM PREVENTION OR RESPONSE, LIFE SUPPORT, OR WEAPONS SYSTEMS ("HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES"). ESRI SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES.

(B) TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, LICENSEE AGREES TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND, AND HOLD ESRI, ITS OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUBCONTRACTORS, LICENSORS, SUCCESSORS, AND ASSIGNS HARMLESS FROM AND AGAINST ANY AND ALL LIABILITY, LOSSES, CLAIMS, EXPENSES (INCLUDING ATTORNEYS' FEES), DEMANDS, OR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH LICENSEE'S USE OR PERMITTING THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES. DELIVERY OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE DOES NOT CONSTITUTE A WAIVER OF THE RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS SET FORTH IN THIS ARTICLE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
          <cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
        <hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
        <cntinst>In the United States-
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact ESRI Support Center by telephone (voice) between 5:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com/; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States-
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI Office.  This information can be found at http://www.esri.com/company/locations.html.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.0.1770</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>The shapefile is converted to SDC (Smart Data Compression) format using either ESRI SDC Data Development Kit Professional 2 (DDKP2) or tools in ArcGIS.  The SDC data set is then loaded into ArcSDE to verify and validate the geometry.</logic>
    <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The geospatial part of this data set was calculated from latitude/longitude coordinates accurate to within 1 arc second of latitude or longitude.

The source data is based upon the use of printed or electronic source graphics which are compiled to meet National Map Accuracy Standards.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Geological Survey (U.S.)</origin>
            <pubdate>19810501</pubdate>
            <title>U.S. Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</title>
            <edition>20080128</edition>
            <geoform>tabular digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, Virginia, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>United States Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>The web page is titled 'U.S. Board on Geographic Names: Domestic Names - State and Topical Gazetteer Download Files'. The data set was last revised on January 28, 2008.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://geonames.usgs.gov/domestic/download_data.htm</onlink>
            <onlink>http://geonames.usgs.gov/docs/stategaz/AllStates.zip</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>19810501</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20080128</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>1974-Present</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date: 19810501, 20080128; ground condition: 1974-Present</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USGS - GNIS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Tele Atlas North America, Inc.</origin>
            <pubdate>200802</pubdate>
            <title>Tele Atlas StreetMap Premium for ArcGIS - North America</title>
            <edition>Version 10.0</edition>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>Tele Atlas StreetMap? Premium for ArcGIS - North America</sername>
              <issue>Version 10.0</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Lebanon, New Hampshire, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>Tele Atlas North America, Inc.</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Provides information about U.S. Large Area Landmarks to code the LABEL_FLAG attribute.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.teleatlas.com/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>DVD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>200802</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Tele Atlas StreetMap Premium - NA v. 10.0</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>GNIS was developed by the U.S. Geological Survey in cooperation with the U.S. Board on Geographic Names (BGN) to promote the standardization of feature names. GNIS is being compiled in phases.
 
GNIS Phase I data compilation and edit - Feature name and attribute data were collected from the largest-scale USGS topographic maps available. These data were compared to the records of the U.S. Board on Geographic Names. This phase is complete.

GNIS Phase II data compilation and edit - Feature name and attribute data are collected from official state and local sources and other approved sources including historical maps and documents. This phase is not complete.

GNIS Maintenance program - Federal and state maintenance cooperators submit new and corrected data in conjunction with their mapping and geographical information system data maintenance programs. The GNIS has an active data gathering and maintenance program. A web-based data date entry and edit application allows authorized users to submit transaction data directly for validation and entry into the database, where it immediately becomes available to all web services and applications. A test and demonstration site is available. Government agencies at all levels are encouraged to join this program. Other organizations and individuals will be considered on a case basis.

Partnerships - the Geographic Names Project enters into partnerships with State names authorities and State and local GIS agencies to integrate name, location, and attribute data in the GNIS with State and local datasets. These partnerships utilize GIS and web technology to automate and simplify data maintenance, ensure data consistency, integrity, and accuracy, and meet the requirements of the Board on Geographic Names for national names standardization. Government agencies at all levels are encouraged to join this program. Other organizations and individuals will be considered on a case basis.</procdesc>
        <procdate>Not complete</procdate>
        <srcprod>USGS - GNIS</srcprod>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Downloaded the tabular files from the U.S. Geological Survey web site. Converted the files (containing latitude and longitude coordinates) to shapefiles in ArcMap? and appended them into one data set. Re-projected Alaska and Hawaii to improve their alignment. Reselected out the nine GNIS data sets based on their class type. Removed features with incorrect coordinates. Adjusted the widths of the NAME attributes. Added the LABEL_FLAG attributes and calculated their values based on whether the features have a corresponding area in U.S. Large Area Landmarks. Converted the data sets to SDC. Created their ArcGIS layer files (.lyr), projection files (.prj), and spatial indices.</procdesc>
        <srcused>USGS - GNIS</srcused>
        <srcused>Tele Atlas StreetMap Premium - NA v. 10.0</srcused>
        <procdate>20080812</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Removed all features where NAME contains 'Squaw'. Converted the data set to SDC. Created ArcGIS layer file (.lyr), projection file (.prj), and spatial indices.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20090811</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>This layer was originally downloaded from the ESRI Data and Maps and Streetmap North America 9.3.1 (2009 Data Update) DVD.  The file was stored in an SDC (Smart Data Compression) format on the DVD.  ArcCatalog 9.3 was utilized to export the SDC file into an ArcSDE 9.3.1 database using the "Feature Class to Feature Class" export tool.</procdesc>
        <srcused>SDC</srcused>
        <procdate>201006</procdate>
        <srcprod>SDE</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>128627</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>ESRI09USglocale</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The points represent physical and cultural geographic features located throughout the United States and its Territories.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>United States Geological Survey</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The name of the geographic feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>United States Geological Survey, United States Board on Geographic Names</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Principles, Policies, and Procedures: Domestic Geographic Names</codesetn>
            <codesets>Principles, Policies, and Procedures: Domestic Geographic Names, By Donald J. Orth, Executive Secretary, Domestic Geographic Names (emeritus) and Roger L. Payne, Executive Secretary, United States Board on Geographic Names and Domestic Geographic Names, Third printing (revised) and Preliminary Online Edition, 1997</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STCTYFIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The combined state/territory and county FIPS code (five-digit number). The combined code uniquely identifies the county in which the geographic feature is located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ELEV_METER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The elevation of the feature in meters relative to sea level.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LABEL_FLAG</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The indicator that the geographic feature has a corresponding area in U.S. Large Area Landmarks.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>The geographic feature does not have a corresponding area in U.S. Large Area Landmarks.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>The geographic feature has a corresponding area in U.S. Large Area Landmarks.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>See use constraints.  Although this data is being distributed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Shapefile</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None; See also use constraints.</fees>
      <ordering>Web-based distribution only.</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports ArcView(r) GIS shapefiles.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20100701</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
