<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>United States. Bureau of Transportation Statistics</origin>
        <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
        <pubdate>20021201</pubdate>
        <title>ESRI Data &amp; Maps 2003 : U.S. National Transportation Atlas Highways</title>
        <edition>2003</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
          <issue>2003</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>ESRI</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>Location: ESRI data &amp; maps 2003  \usa</othercit>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-esri03ushighways</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>U.S. National Transportation Atlas Highways represents rural interstates and arteries; and urban freeways, expressways, interstates, and arteries. U.S. National Transportation Atlas Highways is part of the National Highway Planning Network version 4.0 (line) published by the Federal Highway Administration as part of the National Transportation Atlas Databases for the United States.</abstract>
      <purpose>U.S. National Transportation Atlas Highways provides a comprehensive database of the nation's principal arterial highway system and other National Highway System routes.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:100,000.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2002</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Matches software update releases</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-176.766473</westbc>
        <eastbc>179.391600</eastbc>
        <northbc>71.316578</northbc>
        <southbc>18.912034</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Transportation</themekey>
        <themekey>Roads</themekey>
        <themekey>Express highways</themekey>
        <themekey>Toll roads</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>transportation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>line</themekey>
        <themekey>highways</themekey>
        <themekey>interstates</themekey>
        <themekey>arteries</themekey>
        <themekey>freeways or expressways</themekey>
        <themekey>rural</themekey>
        <themekey>urban</themekey>
        <themekey>transportation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>2002</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
    <useconst>The data are provided under the Harvard University Site License.  These data must be used in compliance with the Site License.  This means that the data are only available for Harvard Affiliates for use on Harvard owned computers. 

The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps for use with ESRI software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, "Geodata" shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Public domain data from U.S. government is freely redistributable with proper metadata and source attribution.

The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
          <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
        <cntinst>In the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>Members of the Geographic Information Systems Laboratory, Pellissippi Research Institute, The University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.2.0.700</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>No duplicate features are present.</logic>
    <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The positional accuracy has a maximal positional error of ?80 meters.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States. Bureau of Transportation Statistics (comp.)</origin>
            <origin>United States. Federal Highway Administration</origin>
            <pubdate>2002</pubdate>
            <title>National Highway Planning Network 4.0 (line)</title>
            <edition>Version 4.0 (line)</edition>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>National Highway Planning Network</sername>
              <issue>4.0 (line)</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, DC, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>Bureau of Transportation Statistics (BTS)</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>From the National Transportation Atlas Databases (NTAD) 2002 CD-ROM.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.bts.gov/gis/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>100000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2002</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>BTS - NHPN</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The general processing steps for the creation of the National Highway Planning Network:
- [1993] Conflation of attributes for rural highways from [National Highway Planning Network V1.1, Bruce Peterson, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1992] to [USGS Digital Line Graph (DLG-3, 1978) Series] road alignments using R-MATCH software developed by the Geographic Information Systems Group, University of Tennessee.
- [1993] Digitizing and conversion of state supplied digital and map data. Line work geodetically controlled to match [USGS Digital Line Graph (DLG-3, 1978) Series] line work.
- [1994] Integration of conflated version of [National Highway Planning Network V1.1, Bruce Peterson, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1992] and assimilated State Departments of Transportation data into a comprehensive topologically integrated network database. States edgematched and National Highway System attributes verified.
- [1997] Integration of supplemental State Departments of Transportation data into the National Highway Planning Network Version 2. National Highway System attributes verified.
- [1998] Integration of intermodal connectors links into the National Highway Planning Network Version 2. States edgematched and National Highway System attributes verified.
- [2001] Update of National Highway System and Intermodal connector links into the National Highway Planning Network Version 4.0. States edgematched and National Highway System attributes verified.</procdesc>
        <procdate>2002</procdate>
        <srcprod>BTS - NHPN</srcprod>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Extracted data set from National Transportation Atlas Databases (NTAD) 2002. Formatted the attributes. Recoded CLASS values of 7, 8, 17, and 19 to 0. Removed Puerto Rico features. Created ArcView legend file (.avl), ArcGIS layer file (.lyr) file, projection file (.prj), and spatial indices.</procdesc>
        <srcused>BTS - NHPN</srcused>
        <procdate>20021112</procdate>
        <srcprod>Shape</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
              <cntper>Data Team</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>380 New York Street</address>
              <city>Redlands</city>
              <state>California</state>
              <postal>92373-8100</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
            <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
            <hours>8:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>In the United States-
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 909-793-3774; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States-
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>This layer was originally downloaded from the ESRI Data and Maps 2003 DVD.  The shapefile was then exported from ArcCatalog 9.1 to an ArcSDE 9.0 database using the "Feature Class to Feature Class" export tool.</procdesc>
        <srcused>Shape</srcused>
        <procdate>20060315</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>163679</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>ESRI03USHIGHWAYS</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The lines represent a comprehensive network database of the principal arterial highway system and other National Highway System routes for United States.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLASS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The assigned functional class description for the road feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>Rural interstate.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>Rural principal arterial.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>6</edomv>
            <edomvd>Rural minor arterial.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>11</edomv>
            <edomvd>Urban interstate.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>12</edomv>
            <edomvd>Urban other freeway or expressway.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>14</edomv>
            <edomvd>Urban principal arterial.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>16</edomv>
            <edomvd>Urban minor arterial.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The descriptive name for the road feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Names for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SOURCE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The original source of the road feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>D</edomv>
            <edomvd>Digitized from State supplied maps.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>H</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>N</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>S</edomv>
            <edomvd>State supplied digital data.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>T</edomv>
            <edomvd>U.S. Census Bureau TIGER/Line files.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>U</edomv>
            <edomvd>USGS Digital Line Graphs.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SIGN1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>A composite field of the primary sign route for the road feature that identifies the type, sign route number that can include a directional indicator, and a qualifier. The first character identifies the type, the following characters up to but not including a blank identify the sign route number that can include a directional indicator, a blank, and the last character identifies the qualifier.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Type, represented by the first character.</edomv>
            <edomvd>(blank) - not signed, I - Interstate, U - U.S. route, S - State route, O - Off-Interstate business marker, C - County route, T - Township, M - Municipal, P - Parkway or Forest route marker, N- None of the above.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Sign route number (can include a directional indicator), represented by all the following characters up to but not including a blank.</edomv>
            <edomvd>Any combination of: A?Z, 0?9, N, S, E, W.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>A blank space.</edomv>
            <edomvd>This separates the sign route number from the qualifier.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Qualifier, represented by the last character when preceded by a blank.</edomv>
            <edomvd>(blank) - No qualifier, not signed, or not applicable; A - Alternate route; B - Business route; P - Bypass; S - Spur; L - Loop; F - Proposed (future); D - Temporary (detour); T - Truck route; N - None of the above.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SIGN2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>A composite field of an alternate sign route for the road feature that identifies the type, sign route number that can include a directional indicator, and a qualifier. The first character identifies the type, the following characters up to but not including a blank identify the sign route number that can include a directional indicator, a blank, and the last character identifies the qualifier.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Type, represented by the first character.</edomv>
            <edomvd>(blank) - not signed, I - Interstate, U - U.S. route, S - State route, O - Off-Interstate business marker, C - County route, T - Township, M - Municipal, P - Parkway or Forest route marker, N- None of the above.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Sign route number (can include a directional indicator), represented by all the following characters up to but not including a blank.</edomv>
            <edomvd>Any combination of: A?Z, 0?9, N, S, E, W.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>A blank space.</edomv>
            <edomvd>This separates the sign route number from the qualifier.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Qualifier, represented by the last character when preceded by a blank.</edomv>
            <edomvd>(blank) - No qualifier, not signed, or not applicable; A - Alternate route; B - Business route; P - Bypass; S - Spur; L - Loop; F - Proposed (future); D - Temporary (detour); T - Truck route; N - None of the above.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SIGN3</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>A composite field of an alternate sign route for the road feature that identifies the type, sign route number that can include a directional indicator, and a qualifier. The first character identifies the type, the following characters up to but not including a blank identify the sign route number that can include a directional indicator, a blank, and the last character identifies the qualifier.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Type, represented by the first character.</edomv>
            <edomvd>(blank) - not signed, I - Interstate, U - U.S. route, S - State route, O - Off-Interstate business marker, C - County route, T - Township, M - Municipal, P - Parkway or Forest route marker, N- None of the above.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Sign route number (can include a directional indicator), represented by all the following characters up to but not including a blank.</edomv>
            <edomvd>Any combination of: A?Z, 0?9, N, S, E, W.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>A blank space.</edomv>
            <edomvd>This separates the sign route number from the qualifier.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Qualifier, represented by the last character when preceded by a blank.</edomv>
            <edomvd>(blank) - No qualifier, not signed, or not applicable; A - Alternate route; B - Business route; P - Bypass; S - Spur; L - Loop; F - Proposed (future); D - Temporary (detour); T - Truck route; N - None of the above.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MILES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The length of the road feature in miles.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Calculated lengths for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>KM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The length of the road feature in kilometers.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Calculated lengths for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOLL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The toll indicator for the road feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>Not a toll road.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>A toll road.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LANES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of lanes in both directions for the road feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>10</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MEDIAN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The type of median for the road feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>Divided highway.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>Undivided highway.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of arc in coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard University Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>See use constraints.  Although this data is being distributed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>SHAPE</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Web-based distribution only.</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports ArcView(r) GIS shapefiles.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
    <metd>20060821</metd>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
