<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</origin>
        <origin>Portland (Or.). Commission of Public Docks.</origin>
        <pubdate>200901</pubdate>
        <title>Portland, Oregon, 1921 (Raster Image)</title>
        <geoform>map</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Cambridge, Massachusetts</pubplace>
          <publish>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-g4294-p6p55-1921-p6</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This layer is a georeferenced raster image of the historic paper map entitled: Industrial map, Portland, Oregon : showing location of port facilities and principal industries with rail connections, compiled and distributed by the Commission of Public Docks. It was published by The Commission of Public Docks in 1921. Scale [ca. 1:21,000]. Covers also a portion of Vancouver, Washington.

The image inside the map neatline is georeferenced to the surface of the earth and fit to the Oregon North State Plane NAD 1983 (in Feet) (Fipszone 3601). All map collar and inset information is also available as part of the raster image, including any inset maps, profiles, statistical tables, directories, text, illustrations, index maps, legends, or other information associated with the principal map. 

This map shows features such as roads, drainage, selected buildings, Commission of Public Docks properties, private shipyards and dry docks, lumber mills, railroads and street car lines, as well as shipyards and railways of Vancouver, Washington. Includes index and inset: Key map, Portland to the sea, showing ship channel, Columbia &amp; Willamette Rivers.

This layer is part of a selection of digitally scanned and georeferenced historic maps from The Harvard Map Collection as part of the Imaging the Urban Environment project.  Maps selected for this project represent major urban areas and cities of the world, at various time periods.  These maps typically portray both natural and manmade features at a large scale. The selection represents a range of regions, originators, ground condition dates, scales, and purposes.</abstract>
      <purpose>Historic paper maps can provide an excellent view of the changes that have occurred in the cultural and physical landscape.  The wide range of information provided on these maps make them useful in the study of historic geography, and urban and rural land use change.  As this map has been georeferenced, it can be used in a GIS as a source or background layer in conjunction with other GIS data.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>1921</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>source map publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-122.862654</westbc>
        <eastbc>-122.541632</eastbc>
        <northbc>45.696850</northbc>
        <southbc>45.429188</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Maps</themekey>
        <themekey>Human settlements</themekey>
        <themekey>Cities and towns</themekey>
        <themekey>Land use</themekey>
        <themekey>Landforms</themekey>
        <themekey>Infrastructure (Economics)</themekey>
        <themekey>Transportation</themekey>
        <themekey>Bodies of water</themekey>
        <themekey>Shipyards</themekey>
        <themekey>Railroads</themekey>
        <themekey>Industrial buildings</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>GNIS</placekt>
        <placekey>Oregon</placekey>
        <placekey>Portland</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>GNIS</placekt>
        <placekey>Washington</placekey>
        <placekey>Vancouver</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard Map Collection</address>
          <address>Pusey Library</address>
          <address>Harvard University</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcGIS 9.2</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>The georeferenced raster is a faithfully reproduced digital image of the original source map. Some differences may be detected between the source graphic used and the raster image due to the RGB values assigned that particular color. The intent is to recreate those colors as near as possible.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <complete>Data completeness for raster digital image files reflect content of the source graphic. Features may have been eliminated or generalized on the source graphic due to scale and legibility constraints</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The horizontal positional accuracy of a raster image is approximately the same as the accuracy of the published source map.  The lack of a greater accuracy is largely the result of the inaccuracies with the original measurements and possible distortions in the original paper map document.  There may also be errors introduced during the digitizing and georeferencing process.  For instance, this raster image was georeferenced to another georeferenced image, which may have its own positional inaccuracies (see "Process Steps").  In most cases, however, errors in the raster image are small compared with sources of error in the original map graphic.  The RMS error for this map is 79.14809 meters.  This value describes how consistent the transformation is between the different control points (links).  The RMS error is only an assessment of the accuracy of the transformation.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Portland (Or.). Commission of Public Docks.</origin>
            <pubdate>1921</pubdate>
            <title>Industrial map, Portland, Oregon : showing location of port facilities and principal industries with rail connections</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Portland, Or.</pubplace>
              <publish>The Commission of Public Docks</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>1 map : col. ; 46 x 121 cm., on sheet 59 x 127 cm.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>21000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1921</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Paper Map</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Source map for raster image</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Production of this raster image began with the scanning of the paper map on a high-resolution scanner: (Betterlight, Super8K2 scanning back camera and ViewFinder 5.x capture software).  Maps were photographed at a copy stand. A vacuum easel was used to keep the maps flat during photography. The imaging specification was designed to produce detailed "Archival Master" images that, to the extent possible, are faithful reproductions of the originals, and that allow for highly detailed screen reproduction and print reproduction at up 1:1. Images in this collection were processed using Adobe Photoshop.  Color and tonal corrections were made using Adobe Photoshop. Image files were viewed on a calibrated monitor. Editing was performed in an ISO 3664 compliant proofing environment. Master Image files were corrected and archived as TIFF files in the sRGB IEC611966-2.1 color-space. When possible files were batch processed using an "action" script derived from edits applied to match a representative sample.</procdesc>
        <srcused>Paper Map</srcused>
        <procdate>2008</procdate>
        <srcprod>TIFF Map Image</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard College Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Digital Imaging and Photography Group</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>D-Level, Room D-30</address>
              <address>Widener Library</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2030</cntvoice>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Using ArcMap 9.2 software, the digital TIFF image was georeferenced to common points located on digital vector shapefiles.  For this image, the following vector shapefile was used as a base map for reference:  ESRI Data and Maps 2007 U.S. and Canada Streets.  The vector data was projected to the 'NAD 1983 Oregon North State Plane (feet)' coordinate system and the TIFF image was subsequently georeferenced to the same projection.  A world file (.tfwx) and an .aux.xml file were automatically generated and saved in association with the digital TIFF image.  See 'Horizontal Accuracy' for the RMS error of this TIFF image.  

Please note that while the image is stored in State Plane coordinates, the projection will need to be defined by the user in order to display the image with other projected data and the world file will need to be stored in the same root directory as the image.</procdesc>
        <srcused>TIFF Map Image</srcused>
        <procdate>2008</procdate>
        <srcprod>Georeferenced Raster Data</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
      <rowcount>6324</rowcount>
      <colcount>13299</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System</gridsysn>
          <spcs>
            <spcszone>3601</spcszone>
            <lambertc>
              <stdparll>44.333333</stdparll>
              <stdparll>46.000000</stdparll>
              <longcm>-120.500000</longcm>
              <latprjo>43.666667</latprjo>
              <feast>8202083.333333</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </lambertc>
          </spcs>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>5.988930</absres>
            <ordres>15.094525</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>The indexes reference a color palette of RGB values from 0 through 255, representing the color value from the original paper sheet map. The colors on that sheet can represent relief, drainage, vegetation, populated places, cultural features, coastal hydrography, transportation features (roads, railroads, tracks and trails), spot elevations and boundaries. The colors are sometimes explained in a legend that is incorporated into the map inset or collar.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>Not applicable.</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard University Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>Although this data set has been developed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>TIFF</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu/</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20090108</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
