<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</origin>
        <origin>Farwell, W. B.</origin>
        <origin>Kunkler, John E.</origin>
        <origin>Pond, E. B.</origin>
        <pubdate>200801</pubdate>
        <title>Chinatown, San Francisco, California 1885 (Raster Image)</title>
        <geoform>map</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Cambridge, Massachusetts</pubplace>
          <publish>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-g4364-s5-2c45g46-1885-f3</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This layer is a georeferenced raster image of the historic paper map entitled: Official map of Chinatown in San Francisco, prepared under the supervision of the special committee of the board of supervisors, July 1885, W.B. Farwell, John E. Kunkler, E.B. Pond. It was engraved &amp; printed by Bosqui Eng. &amp; Print Co. in 1885. Scale [1:480].  This image consists of images of a two sheet source map that have been stitched together using image editing software to create one image. 

The image inside the map neatline is georeferenced to the surface of the earth and fit to the California Zone III State Plane Coordinate System NAD83 (in Feet) (Fipszone 0403). All map collar and inset information is also available as part of the raster image, including any inset maps, profiles, statistical tables, directories, text, illustrations, index maps, legends, or other information associated with the principal map. 

This cadastral map shows features such as roads, buildings with street addresses and types of businesses, and more.  Buildings colored to show: general Chinese occupancy, Chinese gambling houses, Chinese prostitution, Chinese opium resorts, Chinese Joss houses, and White prostitution.

This layer is part of a selection of digitally scanned and georeferenced historic maps from The Harvard Map Collection as part of the Imaging the Urban Environment project.  Maps selected for this project represent major urban areas and cities of the world, at various time periods.  These maps typically portray both natural and manmade features at a large scale. The selection represents a range of regions, originators, ground condition dates, scales, and purposes.</abstract>
      <purpose>Historic paper maps can provide an excellent view of the changes that have occurred in the cultural and physical landscape.  The wide range of information provided on these maps make them useful in the study of historic geography, and urban and rural land use change.  As this map has been georeferenced, it can be used in a GIS as a source or background layer in conjunction with other GIS data.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>1885</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>source map publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-122.408772</westbc>
        <eastbc>-122.404225</eastbc>
        <northbc>37.798098</northbc>
        <southbc>37.791777</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Maps</themekey>
        <themekey>Real property</themekey>
        <themekey>Human settlements</themekey>
        <themekey>Cities and towns</themekey>
        <themekey>Land use</themekey>
        <themekey>Landforms</themekey>
        <themekey>Infrastructure (Economics)</themekey>
        <themekey>Transportation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
        <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>GNIS</placekt>
        <placekey>California</placekey>
        <placekey>San Francisco</placekey>
        <placekey>Chinatown</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard Map Collection</address>
          <address>Pusey Library</address>
          <address>Harvard University</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>The georeferenced raster is a faithfully reproduced digital image of the original source map. Some differences may be detected between the source graphic used and the raster image due to the RGB values assigned that particular color. The intent is to recreate those colors as near as possible.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <complete>Data completeness for raster digital image files reflect content of the source graphic. Features may have been eliminated or generalized on the source graphic due to scale and legibility constraints</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The horizontal positional accuracy of a raster image is approximately the same as the accuracy of the published source map.  The lack of a greater accuracy is largely the result of the inaccuracies with the original measurements and possible distortions in the original paper map document.  There may also be errors introduced during the digitizing and georeferencing process.  In most cases, errors in the raster image are small compared with sources of error in the original map graphic.  The RMS error for this map is 3.48788 feet.  This value describes how consistent the transformation is between the different control points (links).  The RMS error is only an assessment of the accuracy of the transformation.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Farwell, W. B.</origin>
            <origin>Kunkler, John E.</origin>
            <origin>Pond, E. B.</origin>
            <pubdate>1885</pubdate>
            <title>Official map of Chinatown in San Francisco</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>San Francisco</pubplace>
              <publish>Engraved &amp; printed by Bosqui Eng. &amp; Print Co.</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>1 map on 2 sheets : col. ; 62 x 140 cm.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>480</srcscale>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1885</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Paper Map</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Source map for raster image</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Production of this raster image began with the scanning of the paper map on a high-resolution scanner: (Betterlight, Super8K2 scanning back camera and ViewFinder 5.x capture software).  Maps were photographed at a copy stand. A vacuum easel was used to keep the maps flat during photography. The imaging specification was designed to produce detailed "Archival Master" images that, to the extent possible, are faithful reproductions of the originals, and that allow for highly detailed screen reproduction and print reproduction at up 1:1. Images in this collection were processed using Adobe Photoshop.  Color and tonal corrections were made using Adobe Photoshop. Image files were viewed on a calibrated monitor. Editing was performed in an ISO 3664 compliant proofing environment. Master Image files were corrected and archived as TIFF files in the sRGB IEC611966-2.1 color-space. When possible files were batch processed using an "action" script derived from edits applied to match a representative sample.  This image consists of two original images that have been stitched together using Adobe Photoshop.</procdesc>
        <srcused>Paper Map</srcused>
        <procdate>2007</procdate>
        <srcprod>TIFF Map Image</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard College Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Digital Imaging and Photography Group</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>D-Level, Room D-30</address>
              <address>Widener Library</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2030</cntvoice>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The digital TIFF image was georeferenced to common reference points located on digital vector shapefiles.  Vector shapefiles were downloaded from the San Francisco Enterprise GIS website which is the official public portal for the city's geospatial data.  Additional shapefiles from ESRI Data and Maps 2005 and NOAA Vector Shoreline were used if necessary.  For this image, the following vector shapefile(s) were used as base maps for reference: San Francisco Enterprise GIS San Francisco Street Centerlines 2006.  The image was georeferenced to and stored in the NAD83 State Plane California Zone III (feet) (FIPS 0403) coordinate system.  ArcMap 9.2 software was utilized for the georeferencing process, and a .tfwx (world file) and an .aux.xml file were automatically generated and saved in association with the digital image.

Please note that while the image is stored in State Plane coordinates, the projection will need to be defined by the user in order to display the image with other projected data.</procdesc>
        <srcused>TIFF Map Image</srcused>
        <procdate>2007</procdate>
        <srcprod>Georeferenced Raster Data</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
      <rowcount>7465</rowcount>
      <colcount>16792</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Lambert Conformal Conic</mapprojn>
          <lambertc>
            <stdparll>37.066667</stdparll>
            <stdparll>38.433333</stdparll>
            <longcm>-120.500000</longcm>
            <latprjo>36.500000</latprjo>
            <feast>6561666.666667</feast>
            <fnorth>1640416.666667</fnorth>
          </lambertc>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.075504</absres>
            <ordres>0.304924</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>The indexes reference a color palette of RGB values from 0 through 255, representing the color value from the original paper sheet map. The colors on that sheet can represent relief, drainage, vegetation, populated places, cultural features, coastal hydrography, transportation features (roads, railroads, tracks and trails), spot elevations and boundaries. The colors are sometimes explained in a legend that is incorporated into the map inset or collar.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>Not applicable.</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard University Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>Although this data set has been developed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>TIFF</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu/</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20080111</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
