<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</origin>
        <origin>Harvard University. Library. Open Collections Program</origin>
        <origin>United States. Hydrographic Office.</origin>
        <pubdate>200910</pubdate>
        <title>Caribbean Sea, 1885 (Raster Image)</title>
        <geoform>map</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>Open Collections Program at Harvard University. Expeditions and discoveries.</sername>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Cambridge, Massachusetts</pubplace>
          <publish>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-g4392-c3s12-1885-u5-1894</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This layer is a georeferenced raster image of the historic paper map entitled: Contour map of the Caribbean Sea 1885, prepared from data furnished by the U.S. Hydrographic Office, based on the deep-sea soundings of the U.S.C.S.Str. Blake and the U.S.F.Str. Albatross. It was published by the Museum of Comparative Zoology, 1894. Scale [ca. 1:7,300,000]. Covers the Caribbean Sea.

The image inside the map neatline is georeferenced to the surface of the earth and fit to a non-standard 'World Polyconic' projection with the central meridian at 75 degrees west. All map collar and inset information is also available as part of the raster image, including any inset maps, profiles, statistical tables, directories, text, illustrations, index maps, legends, or other information associated with the principal map. 

This map shows features such as drainage, islands, shoreline features, and more. Relief shown by hachures. Depths shown by isolines and soundings.

This layer is part of a selection of digitally scanned and georeferenced historic maps from the Harvard Map Collection and the Harvard University Library as part of the Open Collections Program at Harvard University project: Organizing Our World: Sponsored Exploration and Scientific Discovery in the Modern Age. Maps selected for the project correspond to various expeditions and represent a range of regions, originators, ground condition dates, scales, and purposes.</abstract>
      <purpose>Historic paper maps can provide an excellent view of the changes that have occurred in the cultural and physical landscape.  The wide range of information provided on these maps make them useful in the study of historic geography, and urban and rural land use change.  As this map has been georeferenced, it can be used in a GIS as a source or background layer in conjunction with other GIS data.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>1885</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>source map ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>
-94.521317</westbc>
        <eastbc>
-53.296128</eastbc>
        <northbc>
28.051017</northbc>
        <southbc>
4.600037</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Maps</themekey>
        <themekey>Bathymetric maps</themekey>
        <themekey>Landforms</themekey>
        <themekey>Bodies of water</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
        <themekey>oceans</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>GNS</placekt>
        <placekey>Caribbean Sea</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>
        <placekey>West Indies</placekey>
        <placekey>Central America</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Map Collection, Harvard College Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard Map Collection</address>
          <address>Pusey Library</address>
          <address>Harvard University</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcGIS 9.3</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>The georeferenced raster is a faithfully reproduced digital image of the original source map. Some differences may be detected between the source graphic used and the raster image due to the RGB values assigned that particular color. The intent is to recreate those colors as near as possible.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <complete>Data completeness for raster digital image files reflect content of the source graphic. Features may have been eliminated or generalized on the source graphic due to scale and legibility constraints</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The horizontal positional accuracy of a raster image is approximately the same as the accuracy of the published source map.  The lack of a greater accuracy is largely the result of the inaccuracies with the original measurements and possible distortions in the original paper map document. There may also be errors introduced during the digitizing and georeferencing process.  In most cases, however, errors in the raster image are small compared with sources of error in the original map graphic.  

The RMS error for this map is 10016.65791 meters.  This value describes how consistent the transformation is between the different control points (links).  The RMS error is only an assessment of the accuracy of the transformation.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States. Hydrographic Office.</origin>
            <pubdate>1894</pubdate>
            <title>Contour map of the Caribbean Sea 1885</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Cambridge, Mass.</pubplace>
              <publish>Museum of Comparative Zoology</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>1 map ; 29 x 45 cm.

Appears in: Bulletin. Museum of Comparative Zoology (Geological and Zoological series) 26, part 1 (1894), plate 8.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>7300000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1885</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Paper Map</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Source map for raster image</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Production of this raster image began with the scanning of the paper map on a high-resolution scanner: (Betterlight, Super8K2 scanning back camera and ViewFinder capture software). Loose and bound maps for the OCP Exploration project were photographed at a copy stand. A vacuum easel and/or Plexiglas or points were used to secure loose maps. Foldouts and bound volumes were supported using cradles and built up foam core and matt board supports. The imaging specification was designed to produce detailed "Archival Master" images that, to the extent possible, are faithful reproductions of the originals, that capture the fine detail present in the originals, and that allow for detailed screen reproduction and print reproduction at up 1:1. Images were saved as lossless JPEG2000 files to reduce storage needs and to facilitate variable size viewing. For proofing purposes, original materials were evaluated using GTI EVS viewing booths. Images were evaluated using calibrated Eizo ColorEdge monitors. Tonal and color corrections were made using Adobe Photoshop. Master Image files were corrected and archived in the sRGB IEC611966-2.1 color-space.</procdesc>
        <srcused>Paper Map</srcused>
        <procdate>2008-2009</procdate>
        <srcprod>JP2 Map Image</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard College Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Digital Imaging and Photography Group</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>D-Level, Room D-30</address>
              <address>Widener Library</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2030</cntvoice>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Using ArcMap 9.3 software, the digital JPEG2000 image was georeferenced to common points located on digital vector shapefiles.  For this image, the following vector shapefile was used as a base map for reference:  "World Country Boundaries" from ESRI 2008 Data and Maps.  The vector data was projected to a non-standard 'World Polyconic' projection with the central meridian at 75 degrees west.  The image was subsequently georeferenced to the same projection.   
A world file (.j2w) was automatically generated and saved in association with the digital image.  See 'Horizontal Accuracy' for the RMS error of this image.  

Please note that the projection will need to be defined and modified by the user in order to display the image with other projected data (see 'Horizontal Coordinate System') and the world file will need to be stored in the same root directory as the image.</procdesc>
        <srcused>JP2 Map Image</srcused>
        <procdate>2008-2009</procdate>
        <srcprod>Georeferenced Raster Data</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>
              <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
      <rowcount>4095</rowcount>
      <colcount>6657</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Polyconic</mapprojn>
          <polycon>
            <longcm>-75.000000</longcm>
            <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
            <feast>0.000000</feast>
            <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
          </polycon>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>614.400450</absres>
            <ordres>626.651635</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>The indexes reference a color palette of RGB values from 0 through 255, representing the color value from the original paper sheet map. The colors on that sheet can represent relief, drainage, vegetation, populated places, cultural features, coastal hydrography, transportation features (roads, railroads, tracks and trails), spot elevations and boundaries. The colors are sometimes explained in a legend that is incorporated into the map inset or collar.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>Not applicable.</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard University Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>Although this data set has been developed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>JPEG2000</formname>
          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu/</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20091019</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
