<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Harvard Map Collection</origin>
        <origin>U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census</origin>
        <origin>Massachusetts Institute for Social and Economic Research, University of Massachusetts</origin>
        <origin>Massachusetts Office of Geographic and Environmental Information (MassGIS)</origin>
        <pubdate>200107</pubdate>
        <title>Massachusetts Towns and Household Language Use, 1990</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-meacen-lang90</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This datalayer is a polygon coverage for Massachusetts towns with associated tabular data on language used in the home. This layer was derived from the Massachusetts Electronic Atlas database published by the Harvard Map Collection in 2001.
The Massachusetts Electronic Atlas (MEA) was a collaborative project to provides access, via the Internet, to data about the Commonwealth, its thirteen regional planning agency districts and 351 cities and towns. This dataset is now only available via The Harvard Geospatial Library.</abstract>
      <purpose>This layer is intended for researchers, students, and policy makers for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production. This layer will provide a basemap for layers related to socio-political anaylsis, statistical enumeration and analysis, or to support graphical overlays and analysis with other spatial data. More advanced user applications may focus on demographics, urban and rural land use planning, socio-economic analysis and related areas including defining boundaries, managing assets and facilities, integrating attribute databases with geographic features, spatial analysis, and presentation output.</purpose>
      <supplinf>The following information pertains to the terms used by the U.S. Census Bureau to define those categories included in this layer. Parts of the following were transcribed from the glossary available through the U.S. Census Fact Finder website at: http://factfinder.census.gov

Language Spoken at Home and Linguistic Isolation

Language Spoken at Home:
Data on language spoken at home were derived from the answers to questionnaire items 15a and 15b, which were asked of a sample of persons born before April 1, 1985. Instructions mailed with the 1990 census questionnaire stated that a respondent should mark "Yes" in question 15a if the person sometimes or always spoke a language other than English at home and should not mark "Yes" if a language was spoken only at school or if speaking was limited to a few expressions or slang. For question 15b, respondents were instructed to print the name of the non-English language spoken at home. If the person spoke more than one language other than English, the person was to report the language spoken more often or the language learned first. 

Questions 15a and 15b referred to languages spoken at home in an effort to measure the current use of languages other than English. Persons who knew languages other than English but did not use them at home or who only used them elsewhere were excluded. Persons who reported speaking a language other than English at home may also speak English; however, the questions did not permit determination of the main or dominant language of persons who spoke both English and another language. 

Household Language:
In households where one or more persons (age 5 years old or over) speak a language other than English, the household language assigned to all household members is the non-English language spoken by the first person with a non-English language in the following order: householder, spouse, parent, sibling, child, grandchild, other relative, stepchild, unmarried partner, housemate or roommate, roomer, boarder, or foster child, or other non-relative. Thus, persons who speak only English may have a non-English household language assigned to them in tabulations of persons by household language. 

Linguistic Isolation:
A household in which no person age 14 years or over speaks only English and no person age 14 years or over who speaks a language other than English speaks English "Very well" is classified as "linguistically isolated." All the members of a linguistically isolated household are tabulated as linguistically isolated, including members under age 14 years who may speak only English.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>200107</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-73.508240</westbc>
        <eastbc>-69.927802</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.886818</northbc>
        <southbc>41.237962</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>society</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Demography</themekey>
        <themekey>Population geography</themekey>
        <themekey>Census</themekey>
        <themekey>Languages</themekey>
        <themekey>Multilingualism</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>United States Geological Survey (USGS) Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</placekt>
        <placekey>Massachusetts</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only. Although this data set has been developed  by the Harvard Map Collection and its partners, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the producers as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the producers in the use of this data, or related materials.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Map Collection</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard Map Collection</address>
          <address>Pusey Library</address>
          <address>Harvard University</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 9:00 A.M. to 4:00 P.M. EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>The Massachusetts Electronic Atlas dataset was a joint project of Douglas Carnahan, formerly of the Metropolitan Area Planning Council (MAPC), Richard Gelpke of the Earth and Geographic Sciences Department of the University of Massachusetts at Boston, and David Cobb, Bonnie Burns, Martin von Wyss, and Arlene Olivero of the Harvard Map Collection.  Valuable technical assistance and support has been provided by Environmental Systems Research Institute (ESRI), Peter Girard of ESRI, and the Harvard College Library.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 4; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.3.0.800</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Topological Properties
The attribute accuracy of these files is as precise as the source used during the creation or update of the Massachusetts Electronic Atlas (MEA) database. No specific field tests for attribute accuracy have been conducted on the files.

For persons who indicated that they spoke a language other than English at home, but failed to specify the name of the language, the language was assigned based on the language of other speakers in the household; on the language of a person of the same Spanish origin or detailed race group living in the same or a nearby area; or on a person of the same ancestry or place of birth. In all cases where a person was assigned a non-English language, it was assumed that the language was spoken at home. Persons for whom the name of a language other than English was entered, and for whom question of language use at home was left blank, were assumed to speak that language at home. 

The write-in responses listed in question 15b (specific language spoken) were transcribed onto computer files and coded into more than 380 detailed language categories using an automated coding system. The automated procedure compared write-in responses reported by respondents with entries in a computer dictionary, which initially contained approximately 2,000 language names. The dictionary was updated with a large number of new names, variations in spelling, and a small number of residual categories. Each write-in response was given a numeric code that was associated with one of the detailed categories in the dictionary. If the respondent listed more than one non-English language, only the first was coded. 

The write-in responses represented the names people used for languages they speak. They may not match the names or categories used by linguists. The sets of categories used are sometimes geographic and sometimes linguistic.
The extreme detail in which language names were coded may give a false impression of the linguistic precision of these data. The names used by speakers of a language to identify it may reflect ethnic, geographic, or political affiliations and do not necessarily respect linguistic distinctions. The categories shown in the tabulations were chosen on a number of criteria, such as information about the number of speakers of each language that might be expected in a sample of the United States population.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <complete>Data completeness of the Massachusetts Electronic Atlas (MEA) files reflects the contents of the database at the time the files were created. Data for a given category contain attribute codes that reflect the information portrayed on the original source.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The Massachusetts Electronic Atlas' (MEA) mission to profile the Commonwealth's people and institutions did not require the highest level of positional accuracy.  Coordinates in these files are in decimal degrees and have six implied decimal places.  The positional accuracy of these coordinates may not be as great as the six decimal places suggest. The six-decimal place precision is useful when producing maps as it allows you to place features that are next to each other on the ground in the correct position, relative to each other, on the map without overlap.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Massachusetts Executive Office of Environmental Affairs</origin>
            <title>MassGIS Town Boundaries</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1999</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>MassGIS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Town boundaries derived from MassGIS Town boundaries (with coastline) dataset</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census</origin>
            <title>1990 Census of Population and Housing  Summary Tape File (STF-3)</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>19900401</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Summary Tape File 3 (STF3)</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Tabular data for population statistics derived from this source.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>See Citation information for this datalayer</origin>
            <pubdate>200107</pubdate>
            <title>Massachusetts Electronic Atlas</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>computer program</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>200107</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>MEA Database</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Town boundary data and Attribute tabular data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Tabular data compiled and edited from US Census Bureau STF-3; Town boundary data derived from MassGIS database. Geographic data was obtained by the Harvard Map Collection via CD-ROM. Attribute information was downloaded from Internet as Excel spreadsheet. The spreadsheet was converted to a DBF file, which was joined to the geography using ArcView GIS v 3.2. The join was based on the town name.</procdesc>
        <srcused>1990 Census Summary Tape File 3 (STF3)</srcused>
        <srcused>MassGIS</srcused>
        <procdate>2001</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Map Collection</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Pusey Library</address>
              <address>Harvard University</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 9:00 A.M. to 4:00 P.M. EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The files were processed to shapefile format using the TGR2SHP.exe software program from GIS Tools (version 4.0). The shape file was then imported to an ArcSDE Layer.</procdesc>
        <srcused>MEA Database</srcused>
        <procdate>2003</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library Team</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
              <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 9:00 A.M. to 4:00 P.M. EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
        <srcused>H:\CATALOG\CSS\Metadata\Mass Electronic Atlas\MEA Template Census.xml</srcused>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>611</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altres>1.000000</altres>
        <altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
      </altsys>
    </vertdef>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Language Characteristics in Massachusetts Towns</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Polygons represent Town boundaries with associated tabular data</enttypd>
        <enttypds>MEA; Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOWN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Town Name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUSUBFP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>FIPS Town Code</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CNT</attrlabl>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TIM.MEACEN_LANG90.AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature area in square coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Computed</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Polyline length measured in map units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Computed</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIPS_ST_CD</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>FIPS State + County Code</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CCD_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>US Census Town Code (Census County Division Code)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIPS_TWN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>FIPS Town Code</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP80</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Town Population in 1980</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP90</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Town Population in 1990</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ISLAN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Polygon is (1) / is NOT (0) an island - many towns are composed of many polygons</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassGIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP_CHNG</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Change in Town population between 1980 and 1990</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOWN_NUM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>MassGIS Town-ID Code (alphabetical, 1-351)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassGIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREANAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State and Town or Town Area Name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPALANIS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Spanish language, Linguistically isolated</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPANOTIS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Spanish language, Not linguistically isolated</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>A_PLANIS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Asian or Pacific Island language, Linguistically isolated</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>A_PNOTIS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Asian or Pacific Island language, Not linguistically isolated</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTHLANIS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Other language, Linguistically isolated</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTHNOTIS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Other language, Not linguistically isolated</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPONLENG</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - English</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPGERMAN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - German</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPYIDISH</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Yiddish</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPOTHGER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Other West Germanic</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes Afrikaans, Dutch, Pensylvania Dutch</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPSCANDI</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Scandinavian</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes Danish, Norwegian, Swedish</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPGREEK</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Greek</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPINDIC</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Indic</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes Hindi, Bengali, Gujarathi, Punjabi, Romany, Sinhalese</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPITALIA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Italian</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPFRENCH</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - French</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes French, Cajun, French Creole</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPPORTUG</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Portugese</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPSPANIS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Spanish</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes Spanish, Ladino</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPPOLISH</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Polish</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPRUSSIA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Russian</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPSOSLAV</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - South Slavic</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes Serbocroatian, Bulgarian, Macedonian, Slovene</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPOTHSLA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Other Slavic</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes Czech, Slovak, Ukranian</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPOTGIEU</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home -</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPARABIC</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Arabic</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPTAGALO</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Tagalog</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPCHINES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Chinese</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPHUNGAR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Hungarian</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPJAPAN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Japanese</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPMONKHM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Mon-Khmer</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes Cambodian</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPKOREAN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Korean</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPNATAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Native North American languages</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPVIETNA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Vietnamese</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPOTHLAN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Language Spoken at Home - Other languages</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>Includes: Amharic, Syriac, Finnish, Hebrew, Languages of Central and South America, Other Languages of Africa (partial list)</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature area in square coverage units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Computed</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Polyline length in map units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Computed</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Shape</formname>
          <filedec>Zip</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Web based distribution only. http://hgl.harvard.edu</ordering>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20040227</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntper>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
