<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Harvard Map Collection</origin>
        <origin>U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census</origin>
        <origin>Massachusetts Institute for Social and Economic Research, University of Massachusetts</origin>
        <origin>Massachusetts Office of Geographic and Environmental Information (MassGIS)</origin>
        <pubdate>200107</pubdate>
        <title>Massachusetts Municipal Expenditures, 1985-2001</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-meafnnc8701</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This datalayer is a polygon coverage for Massachusetts towns which displays town boundaries and municipal general fund expenitures organized by function (Police, Fire, Recreation, etc.) for the Fiscal Years 1987 through 2001.

This layer was derived from the Massachusetts Electronic Atlas database published by the Harvard Map Collection in 2001. For more information on the definitions, data sources and process steps please read the "Supplemental Information" and "Data Quality" sections which follow.
The Massachusetts Electronic Atlas (MEA) was a collaborative project to provides access, via the Internet, to data about the Commonwealth, its thirteen regional planning agency districts and 351 cities and towns. This dataset is now only available via The Harvard Geospatial Library.</abstract>
      <purpose>This layer is intended for researchers, students, and policy makers for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production. This layer will provide a basemap for layers related to socio-political anaylsis, statistical enumeration and analysis, or to support graphical overlays and analysis with other spatial data. More advanced user applications may focus on demographics, urban and rural land use planning, socio-economic analysis and related areas including defining boundaries, managing assets and facilities, integrating attribute databases with geographic features, spatial analysis, and presentation output.</purpose>
      <supplinf>The attribute data in this layer was derived from the Commonwealth of Massachusetts Department of Revenue, Division of Local Services, Municipal Data Bank/ Local Aid Section "Fiscal Year General Fund Expenditures" databases, known as "Schedule A Reports"

General Fund Expenditure data are gathered and obtained through the Schedule A that is submitted to the Division of Local Services by Local Government Officials.  Expenditures are from the general fund and do not reflect spending from special revenue, enterprise, capital projects, or trust funds.  This may result in wide variations among communities in the "other public works" category, because many communities account for spending on sewer, water, utilities, and other public works functions in enterprise or special revenue funds.
Capital outlay and construction expenditures are also excluded in order to encourage fair comparisons. Intergovernmental transfers within departmental budgets, such as regional school assessments, are reported within their respective functions (i.e. education) and not in the "intergovernmental" column.

Schedule A: Actual Revenues and Expenditures in Each Fiscal Year
Town accountants and city auditors submit this report in the fall after the close of the fiscal year. Individual communities' data can be released as soon as their reports have been reviewed and edited; the data base for all cities and towns often takes up to a year to finalize. Based upon the Uniform Municipal Accounting System (UMAS), revenues and expenditures are reported for general, special revenue, capital project, enterprise and trust funds. 

Revenues are broken into categories such as taxes, penalties and interest, charges for services, licenses and permits, special assessments, fines, earnings on investments, and intergovernmental receipts. 
Expenditures are submitted in great detail. For analytic purposes, they are often 
aggregated into functional categories as they appear here.

The Municipal Data Bank collects, analyzes and distributes financial, demographic and economic data on Massachusetts cities and towns. Financial data comes from a series of reports that municipalities submit annually to the Division of Local Services. Demographic and economic data is collected from other state and federal agencies. The Data Bank develops and maintains systems to collect and distribute the information, assists users in interpretation and use, participates in research projects with other agencies and organizations, and distributes reports which summarize data analyses.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>FY1987</begdate>
          <enddate>FY2001</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-73.508240</westbc>
        <eastbc>-69.927802</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.886818</northbc>
        <southbc>41.237962</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>economy</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Municipal budgets</themekey>
        <themekey>Municipal government</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>United States Geological Survey (USGS) Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</placekt>
        <placekey>Massachusetts</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only. Although this data set has been developed  by the Harvard Map Collection and its partners, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the producers as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the producers in the use of this data, or related materials.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Map Collection</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard Map Collection</address>
          <address>Pusey Library</address>
          <address>Harvard University</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 9:00 A.M. to 4:00 P.M. EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>The Massachusetts Electronic Atlas dataset was a joint project of Douglas Carnahan, formerly of the Metropolitan Area Planning Council (MAPC), Richard Gelpke of the Earth and Geographic Sciences Department of the University of Massachusetts at Boston, and David Cobb, Bonnie Burns, Martin von Wyss, and Arlene Olivero of the Harvard Map Collection.  Valuable technical assistance and support has been provided by Environmental Systems Research Institute (ESRI), Peter Girard of ESRI, and the Harvard College Library.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 4; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.3.0.800</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Topological Properties
The attribute accuracy of these files is as precise as the source used during the creation or update of the Massachusetts Electronic Atlas (MEA) database. No specific field tests for attribute accuracy have been conducted on the files.

All Attributes for FY87 are defined here and the remaining years follow the same pattern listing expenditures for each fiscal year in the order of: 
General Government; Police; Fire; Other Public Safety; Education; Public Works- Highway; Other Public Works; Health and Welfare; Culture and Recreation; Debt Services; Fixed Costs; Other; and Total Expenditures.
Beginning in FY88 an attribute titled "Inter-Governmental" was added.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <complete>Data completeness of the Massachusetts Electronic Atlas (MEA) files reflects the contents of the database at the time the files were created. Data for a given category contain attribute codes that reflect the information portrayed on the original source.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The Massachusetts Electronic Atlas' (MEA) mission to profile the Commonwealth's people and institutions did not require the highest level of positional accuracy.  Coordinates in these files are in decimal degrees and have six implied decimal places.  The six-decimal place precision is useful when producing maps as it allows you to place features that are next to each other on the ground in the correct position, relative to each other, on the map without overlap.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Commonwealth of Massachusetts, Department of Revenue, Division of Local Services, Municipal Data Bank/ Local Aid Section</origin>
            <title>Municipal Data Bank Schedule A Reports</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>computer program</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>FY1987</begdate>
              <enddate>FY2001</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>MassDOR</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Provided tabular data on municipal expenditures per fiscal year</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <title>MassGIS Town Boundaries</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1999</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>MassGIS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Town boundaries derived from MassGIS datasets</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Tabular data compiled and edited from Massachusetts Department of Revenue Division of Local Services, Municipal Data Bank Schedule A datafiles. Boundary data derived from MassGIS Towns datalayer. The MassDOR attribute file was joined to the geography using ArcView GIS v 3.2. The join was based on the town name.</procdesc>
        <srcused>MassDOR</srcused>
        <srcused>MassGIS</srcused>
        <procdate>Unknown</procdate>
        <srcprod>MEA Database</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Map Collection</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Pusey Library</address>
              <address>Harvard University</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 9:00 A.M. to 4:00 P.M. EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The files were processed to shapefile format using the TGR2SHP.exe software program from GIS Tools (version 4.0). The shape file was then imported to an ArcSDE Layer.</procdesc>
        <srcused>MEA Database</srcused>
        <procdate>2003</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library Team</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Harvard University Library</address>
              <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
              <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 9:00 A.M. to 4:00 P.M. EST-USA</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm Name="TIM.MEAFNNC8701">
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>611</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.000001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altres>1.000000</altres>
        <altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
      </altsys>
    </vertdef>
  </spref>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Shape</formname>
          <filedec>Zip</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Web based distribution only. http://hgl.harvard.edu</ordering>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20040506</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntper>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Harvard University Library</address>
          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed Name="TIM.MEAFNNC8701">
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Municipal Expenditures by Town</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Polygons represent town boundaries with associated attribute data</enttypd>
        <enttypds>MassDOR; MEA</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOWN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Town Name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassGIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DOR_CODE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Department of Revenue Town Code</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GEN_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Government Expenditures, FY87 (Legislative, Executive, Accountant/Auditor, Collector, Treasurer, Law Department Town/City Counsel,  Public Building/Properties Maintenance,  Assessors, Operation Support, License and Registration, Land Uses,  Conservation Commission and other)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1986</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1987</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Police Department Expenditures, FY87</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Fire Department Expenditures, FY87</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Other Public Safety Expenditures, FY87 (Emergency Medical Services, Inspection and other.)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Education Expenditures, FY87</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Public Works Highway Expenditures, FY87</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Other Public Works Expenditures, FY87 (Streets, Snow &amp; Ice, Highway/Streets other, Waste Collection &amp; Disposal,  Sewerage Collection &amp; Disposal, Water Distribution, Parking Garage, Street Lighting, and other.)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WK_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Health and Welfare Expenditures, FY87 (Health Services, Clinical Services, Special Program, Veteran's Services and other.)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_WK_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Culture and Recreation Expenditures, FY87 (Library, Recreation, Parks, Historical Commission, Celebrations and other.)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Debt Service Expenditures, FY87 (Retirement of Debt Principal, Interest on Long Term Debt, Interest on Short Term Debt and Other Interest)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Fixed Cost Expenditures, FY87 (Workers' Compensation, Unemployment, Health Insurance, other Employee Benefits and Retirement.)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Other Expenditures, FY87 (Court Judges and Other Unclassified Expenditures.)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_87</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY87</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DPT_SV_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INGOV_88</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Intergovernmental Assessments</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_88</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_88</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY88</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>MassDOR</attrdefs>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1987</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1988</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_89</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_89</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY89</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1988</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1989</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DPT_SV_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EXP_90</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_90</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY90</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1989</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1990</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_91</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_91</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY91</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1990</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1991</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INT_GOV_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_92</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_92</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY92</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1991</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1992</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTHT_WF_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INT_GOV_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_93</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_93</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY93</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1992</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1993</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PUBLIC_WOR</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_94</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_94</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY94</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1993</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1994</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTHWK_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EXP_95</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_95</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY95</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1994</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1995</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WH_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EXP_96</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_96</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY96</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1995</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1996</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INT_GOV_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_97</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_97</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY97</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1996</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1997</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_98</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_98</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY98</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1997</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1998</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_99</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_99</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY99</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1998</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 1999</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WK_HWY_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_WK_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HTH_WF_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_00</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_00</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY00</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 1999</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 2000</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GOV_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POLICE_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIRE_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_SF_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EDUC_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PUB_WK_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HMN_SV_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLT_REC_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DBT_SV_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FX_CST_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INTGOV_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OTH_EX_01</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTL_01</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General Fund Expenditures Total, FY01</attrdef>
        <begdatea>July 1, 2000</begdatea>
        <enddatea>June 30, 2001</enddatea>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature area measured in square map units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Computed</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Polyline length measured in map units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Computed</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
</metadata>
