<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>City of Newton GIS</origin>
        <pubdate>1998?</pubdate>
        <title>Street Centerlines - City of Newton</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>https://hgl.harvard.edu/catalog/harvard-nwtnstrtclln</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This data layer contains a single line representation of all Newton's streets. There are several duplicate street names in Newton.</abstract>
      <purpose>This layer is intended for researchers, students, and policy makers for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production, or to provide a basemap to support graphical overlays and analysis with other spatial data.

This layer will provide a basemap for layers related to transportation issues as well as more advanced user applications which may focus on urban planning and policy, public works, or utilities purposes (including defining boundaries, managing assets and facilities, integrating attribute databases with geographic features, spatial analysis, and presentation output.)</purpose>
      <supplinf>This data layer is maintained as needed by the City of Newton.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>1998?</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-71.267956</westbc>
        <eastbc>-71.157456</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.366718</northbc>
        <southbc>42.288309</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>transportation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>HGL Category Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Municipal</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>
        <themekey>Streets</themekey>
        <themekey>Roads</themekey>
        <themekey>Transportation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>GNIS</placekt>
        <placekey>Newton</placekey>
        <placekey>Massachusetts</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access is granted to licensee (Harvard University) only. Available only to Harvard University affiliates.</accconst>
    <useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>City of Newton GIS</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Administrator</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Information Technology Department</address>
          <address>City Hall  Room 107</address>
          <address>1000 Commonwealth Avenue</address>
          <city>Newton Center</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02459-1400</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-796-1180</cntvoice>
        <cntvoice>617-796-1000</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>GIS data supplied by City of Newton GIS.</datacred>
    <secinfo>
      <secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
    </secinfo>
    <native>Microsoft Windows NT Version 4.0 (Build 1381) Service Pack 6; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.2.0.700</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>DPW-ID Attribute
The city's Public Works Department presently manages its' street maintenance activities using Hansen Inc.'s Infrastructure Management System (IMS).  A pre-requisite for creating the street database in IMS was creating a unique numbering scheme for each street and each segment (street block) of each street.  For example, Adams Ave. has seven blocks, created by intersections with six cross streets.  The unique numbers for those seven blocks are 8001, 8002, ..., 8007.  In other words, each street name is assigned a unique number series (8000 in the above example) and each segment of that street has a unique sequential number (e.g., 8001) in that series.  This same number system is used in the GIS database for the Street Center Line coverage.  Each record in the street center-line coverage .AAT includes the attribute DPW-ID; it contains the unique IMS street number for that record.  Note that some of the arcs in the street center line coverage, notably those representing the Massachusetts Turnpike, are not uniquely numbered; instead they have the number 10000.  Also, some streets have segments that are not contiguous (e.g., Washington St, Rokeby Rd.).  Finally, some streets are divided so that one direction of traffic is on a portion of road that is physically separate from the other direction (e.g., Commonwealth Ave, Washington St., Washington Pk.); the numbering scheme described above does not work for those streets.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>For layers containing line or polygon features, Newton's data layers are "topologically clean". This was verified with Arc/Info software version 7.x in 1998 and is an ongoing part of data maintenance for the relevant data layers.</logic>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The objective in creating this data layer was simply to have a line representing each street block fall in the street right-of-way.  Streets represented include both public and private and built and un-built ("paper") streets.

From: PARCELS Horizontal Accuracy Report
No systematic and quantitative review of property boundary accuracy has ever been conducted.  However, several qualitative observations based on experience using the data are possible.  The street right-of-way lines overlay the orthophoto base map very well, falling on or close to the apparent back-of-sidewalk visible on the photos.The edge-of-pavement data layer was compiled from aerial photography for Boston Edison to an absolute accuracy specification of +/- 2.5 feet.  Again, the right-of-way lines match up well in this comparison.  Less is known about the accuracy of the internal property boundaries.  Casual observations suggest they are sometimes as accurate as the right-of-way lines and sometimes much less.  Some observations of boundary line discrepancies relative to property boundary lines such as fences and hedges visible on the orthophotos indicate that internal property boundaries may be off by at least +/- 5 feet</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>City of Newton GIS</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <title>Newton GIS Parcels Layer</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>1000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>computer program</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1992?</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>PARCELS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Some Attribute information for this layer were derived from the PARCELS datalayer.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Lines representing each street were created using "heads-up digitizing" with the Parcels data layer as a guide.

From: PARCELS Datalayer Process Steps
In 1979, Newton awarded a contract to Burger Associates from Ohio to develop new maps at a uniform scale.  Burger Associates took aerial photographs of the city and used them to produce orthophotographs and a planimetric base map.  The base map included topographic contours with a two-foot contour interval.  The new parcel maps were compiled by photo reducing or enlarging the existing maps (most of which were at 1:480 scale) to the 1:1000 compilation scale.  The maps were adjusted to fit features such as the apparent back-of-sidewalk on the planimetric base map, and then property boundaries were traced onto the planimetric base map.  These property lines were then digitized using computer assisted drafting (CAD) software.   Two map sets were delivered, one at 1:1000 (1" = 83.3') scale (a metric scale produced to satisfy the requirements of the state funding involved) and one at 1:480 scale (1" = 40').

In late 1991, Newton contracted with Applied Geographics, Inc. (Boston, MA) for development of an Arc/Info version of its property parcels.  This was accomplished by converting the 168 CAD files (one each per 1:1000 scale sheet) provided by Burger Associates to Arc/Info format.  Once the CAD files were converted to Arc/Info, additional processing included:

Closing parcels bordering the Charles River; they were not closed after the DXF to Arc conversion because the river boundary in the DXF file was stored as a dashed line.  A replacement line was digitized from the 1:1000 scale assessor map sheets.  
Property boundaries in the DXF files usually did not create closed polygons; this was corrected through a combination of automated procedures and interactive editing.
Boundaries crossing CAD file limits had to be edge-matched. In many instances rounded parcel corners collapsed (becoming straight or jagged) when the DXF files were converted to Arc format.  Many, but not all of these were corrected.  Some additional work has been completed on this, but the problem persists.
A polygon label point was created for each parcel and the correct section/block/lot identifier added. The property splits and mergers from 1979 to April 1992 were incorporated.

This is a very complete record of property boundaries as it has been the focus of a lot of checking and other work that has reduced errors.  Remaining problems involve tiny sliver parcels at the edge of the city, which may or may not be real.  More work checking these situations needs to be performed.  In addition, there are instances of cul-de-sacs where the properties on each side at the end were not actually separate topologically because of a tiny sliver between the end of the cul-de-sac and the property line against which it terminates.  This issue is further complicated because some of these situations correctly depict the property shape!  These problems notwithstanding, this data layer records over 99.9% of all properties in the city.</procdesc>
        <procdate>Unknown</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Newton GIS</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The original shape file was imported to an ArcSDE Layer.</procdesc>
        <procdate>200208</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library Team</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Office of Information Systems</address>
              <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
              <city>Cambridge</city>
              <state>MA</state>
              <postal>02138</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Metadata created, imported and edited</procdesc>
        <procdate>20021008</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntper>
              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>4296</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System</gridsysn>
          <spcs>
            <spcszone>2001</spcszone>
            <lambertc>
              <stdparll>41.716667</stdparll>
              <stdparll>42.683333</stdparll>
              <longcm>-71.500000</longcm>
              <latprjo>41.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>656166.666667</feast>
              <fnorth>2460625.000000</fnorth>
            </lambertc>
          </spcs>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000476</absres>
            <ordres>0.000476</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altdatum>National Geodetic Vertical Datum of 1929</altdatum>
        <altres>1.000000</altres>
        <altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
      </altsys>
    </vertdef>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Street Centerlines</enttypl>
        <enttypd>ESRI Shapefile. Lines represent street centerlines</enttypd>
        <enttypds>ESRI, Newton GIS</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FNODE_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal node number for the beginning of an arc (From-node).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TNODE_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal node number for the end of an arc (To-node)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LPOLY_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal node number for the left polygon</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>RPOLY_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal node number for the right polygon</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LENGTH</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internally calculated length of feature in map units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STREETCL_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal Feature Identifier</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STREETCL_I</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal Feature Identifier</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DPW_ID_OLD</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique number for each street and each segment (street block) of each street</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton Department of Public Works, Hansen Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>See Attribute Accuracy Report</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DPW_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique number for each street and each segment (street block) of each street</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton Department of Public Works, Hansen Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrvai>
          <attrva>See Attribute Accuracy Report</attrva>
        </attrvai>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LF</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The left-From address</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The left-To address</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>RF</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The right-From address</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>RT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The right-To address</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATUS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indicates if street is public or private</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>[Blank]</edomv>
            <edomvd>Public Street</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>PRIVATE</edomv>
            <edomvd>Private Street</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>UP_DATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Record of the type of edits and additions to street segment identifiers.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NO CHANGE</edomv>
            <edomvd>Some segments in the street have changed, but not that segment</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SPLIT</edomv>
            <edomvd>DPW-ID of the segment has not changed, the segment was split into two</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NEWID</edomv>
            <edomvd>Segment has a new DPW-ID because it was split off from an existing segment</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NEW-SEG</edomv>
            <edomvd>A newly created segment of the street (includes all of new streets)</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EXCLUSION</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indicates if city ordinance excludes heavy vehicles from this street segment</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Y</edomv>
            <edomvd>Heavy vehicles excluded</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>[Blank]</edomv>
            <edomvd>Heavy vehicles not excluded</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ONEWAY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Values refer to the topological direction of the "one way"</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FT</edomv>
            <edomvd>From To</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>TF</edomv>
            <edomvd>To From</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>B</edomv>
            <edomvd>Both Directions</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>N</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Traffic</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ARTERY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Identifies major streets and residential arteries</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Y</edomv>
            <edomvd>Major street or residential artery</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>[Blank]</edomv>
            <edomvd>Not a major street or artery</edomvd>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Identifies streets where the legal right-of-way exists but where no street has been constructed or abandoned streets.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>PAPER</edomv>
            <edomvd>Paper Streets, right-of-way exists, no street constructed</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>ABANDONED</edomv>
            <edomvd>Abandoned Streets</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Newton GIS</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PRE_DIR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street prefix cardinal direction</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>N</edomv>
            <edomvd>North</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>E</edomv>
            <edomvd>East</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>S</edomv>
            <edomvd>South</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>W</edomv>
            <edomvd>West</edomvd>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PRE_TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street type prefix</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STREET_NAM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STREET_TYP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street type (e.g., Ave, Rd, St, etc)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SUF_DIR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street suffix cardinal direction</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Newton GIS</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NWTNSTRTCLLN.FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internally calculated length of feature in map units</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office of Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Shape</formname>
          <filedec>Zip</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Web based distribution only. http://hgl.harvard.edu</ordering>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20021015</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntper>
          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Office of Information Systems</address>
          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02138</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>617-295-12417</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>
        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metsi>
      <metsc>Unclassified</metsc>
    </metsi>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
